<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Not Your Mother's Mormonism</title>
    <description>Not Your Mother's Mormonism — A Personal Blog For Mormons, ExMormons And Everyone In Between</description>
    <link>https://NotYourMothersMormonism.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://NotYourMothersMormonism.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 03:15:55 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 03:15:55 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.0</generator>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Title Page: Book of Mormon</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;H&lt;/span&gt;ello, friends! This is the first post in an ongoing series of what will be an in-depth analysis of the Book of Mormon. The Book of Mormon—whether you believe it is divine and historical or a 19th-century work of pseudepigrapha—has deeply influenced millions of people. I have read and studied this book over thirty times in my life. Now I will be studying it from a new perspective because I have changed my position from a true believing member of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints to a disbeliever. I now view the Book of Mormon as non-historical 19th-century Bible fan fiction fabricated by Joseph Smith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of my friends and family, who will be the most inclined to read my posts, hold the Book of Mormon as the infallible word of God. I want the believer to know that I will do my best to be respectful while also sharing arguments, history, and perspectives that bring the honest seeker of truth to a different vantage point. If you follow along I think we will both come out of this more informed and enlightened on the subject. I welcome all criticism, corrections, and comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeffery R. Holland said a member cannot leave the church without “crawling over or under or around the Book of Mormon to make that exit.”&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#references&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; That cannot be said of me or the thousands of post-Mormons that have left because of major issues in the book. Let’s dive in and see for ourselves what is in this controversial and fascinating book, starting from the title page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-title-page&quot;&gt;THE TITLE PAGE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2020-03-22/bom-title-page.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Title page of The Book of Mormon submitted to the Library of Congress for copyright registration. Filed 11 June 1829.&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Title page of The Book of Mormon submitted to the Library of Congress for copyright registration. Filed 11 June 1829.²&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;who-wrote-the-title-page&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHO WROTE THE TITLE PAGE?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first edition of the Book of Mormon has Joseph Smith as the “author and proprietor”, however, this is not what Joseph Smith claimed. Using “author and proprietor” was used to comply with copyright laws. Smith claimed to have translated the Book of Mormon from a set of gold plates in an unknown language that the book itself refers to as “reformed Egyptian.”&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#references&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Smith, “the title-page of the Book of Mormon is a literal translation, taken from the very last leaf, on the left hand side of the collection or book of plates, which contained the record which has been translated, the language of the whole running the same as all Hebrew writing in general; and that said title page is not by any means a modern composition, either of mine or of any other man who has lived or does live in this generation.”&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#references&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the believers perspective it can be concluded that the title page was translated using the same method David Whitmer described:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Joseph Smith put the seer stone into a hat, and put his face in the hat, drawing it closely around his face to exclude the light; and in the darkness the spiritual light would shine. A piece of something resembling parchment would appear, and on that appeared the writing. One character at a time would appear, and under it was the interpretation in English. Brother Joseph would read off the English to Oliver Cowdery, who was his principal scribe, and when it was written down and repeated to Brother Joseph to see if it was correct, then it would disappear, and another character with the interpretation would appear. Thus the Book of Mormon was translated by the gift and power of God, and not by any power of man.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#references&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2020-03-22/joseph-smith-money.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Title page of The Book of Mormon submitted to the Library of Congress for copyright registration. Filed 11 June 1829.&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Between 1819-1827, Joseph made money as a money digger. His role in these excursions was to use a stone in the bottom of his white top hat to view treasure beneath the earth and tell others where to dig. This image imagines what Joseph would have looked like during this period. It was made using the youngest available photos of his sons, his death mask, and a body borrowed from a contemporary. https://www.knowbrotherjoseph.com/young-joseph&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One can picture Smith putting his face in his white stovepipe hat while dictating the title page to a scribe while the plates were supposedly hidden in the woods. The title page was “translated” by Smith &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; the storyline of the book was complete using his chocolate-colored seer stone which originally belonged to Smith’s treasure seeking companion Willard Chase. The seer stone was later referred to as a Urim and Thummim by Smith’s followers four years after the publication of the book.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#references&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connecting the peep stone to the ancient Urim and Thummim referred to in the Bible faired well for Mormonism in that it distracted new followers from connecting the stone with Smith’s earlier money digs, even though Aaron’s biblical Urim and Thummim has little resemblance to 19th-century peep stones. The term Urim and Thummim is still heavily used today to describe the translation process while the stonepipe hat and peep stone receive little attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Book of Mormon claims that a prophet-historian named Mormon abridged the history of the people in the Americas by engraving the reformed Egyptian hieroglyphics on golden plates in ~400 AD. Mormon’s son Moroni inherited the golden records and abridged an additional 24 plates of gold from “the people of Jared” (aka “Jaredites”) and added commentary of his own before burying the plates in upstate New York for Smith to find one thousand four hundred years later. The title page was the last leaf Moroni engraved, according to Smith. It’s as if Moroni lived in the 19th-century since title pages were first used in the 16th century. The title page should thus be regarded by the faithful as truly miraculous since Moroni wrote it before its invention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, who is the author of the title page of the Book of Mormon? In 1842 Joseph Smith claimed Moroni was. Some LDS scholars make an argument that Mormon authored the first paragraph and Moroni authored the second paragraph.⁷ A more compelling answer is that Joseph Smith is the author of the title page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How could it be concluded that Smith is the author of the title page? After the 116 page manuscript was lost Joseph continued “translating” the Book of Mormon from Mosiah to Moroni, perhaps holding out hope that the lost manuscript would be found. After the Book of Moroni was complete, Smith dictated 1 Nephi to The Words of Mormon from the conveniently included small plates of Nephi which Mormon inserted at the end of his abridgment. Another miracle that believing members seem to overlook is that Nephi must have created his small plates to be the same dimensions to be included in Mormon’s D-shaped ring plates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smith obtained the copyright to the Book of Mormon from E. B. Grandin on June 11th, 1829. During this time, Smith would have been finishing the remainder of 2 Nephi which we can compare to the title page and look for similarities. 2 Nephi 26:12-13 reads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;12 And as I spake concerning the &lt;strong&gt;convincing of the Jews&lt;/strong&gt;, that Jesus is the very Christ, it must needs be that the &lt;strong&gt;Gentiles be convinced&lt;/strong&gt; also that &lt;strong&gt;Jesus is the Christ, the Eternal God&lt;/strong&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;13 And that he &lt;strong&gt;manifesteth himself&lt;/strong&gt; unto all those who believe in him, by the power of the Holy Ghost; yea, unto every nation, kindred, tongue, and people, working mighty miracles, signs, and wonders, among the children of men according to their faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bolded text in the above passage has striking similarities with the title page—as if Nephi and Moroni are the same author—especially when considering that “JESUS is the CHRIST, the ETERNAL GOD” only appears in these two places in the entire Book of Mormon , linking Joseph as the author of both texts.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#references&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-last-leaf--charles-anthon&quot;&gt;THE LAST LEAF &amp;amp; CHARLES ANTHON&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if we could see what the last leaf of the gold plates—which supposedly contained the text of the title page of the Book of Mormon—looked like? Would it prove Joseph’s seership or be another blunder like the papyri Smith translated as the Book of Abraham? We don’t have the plates to examine but we might be able to re-construct what Smith claimed the last leaf looked like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin Harris, who funded the Book of Mormon translation and publication, wanted evidence of the authenticity of the plates for his own benefit and to ease the criticism that he was being scammed by Smith. Smith prepared a facsimile for Harris to take to “learned” scholars and linguists that Harris hoped would silence the critics and reassure his investment. The document that Smith produced for Harris—which has been lost to history but described by Charles Anthon, Charles W. Brown, Harris’ neighbor Francis Gladden Bishop and Joseph Smith Sr.—was described as the last leaf and reportedly looked similar to the Aztec calendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The facsimile’s connection with the last leaf and title page is described best by Don Bradley:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Martin took the facsimile of the final, sealed plate first to politician, scholar, and world traveler Luther Bradish in Albany and then to the distinguished scholars Samuel Mitchill and Charles Anthon in New York City. According to Anthon, the document carried by Martin Harris was a “transcript of a page of the Golden Bible”—i.e., a facsimile of a single plate from the set Joseph had recovered. But which plate? Joseph’s mother recalled him wanting to send an “alphabet” from the plates, and Joseph’s father recounted that such an alphabet was contained on the last plate of the book of plates. Fitting together the various puzzle pieces provided by Anthon, Joseph Sr., and Lucy Mack Smith, it appears that what Joseph sent to the scholars was a transcript or facsimile of the concluding plate…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Six years after examining the facsimile Anthon described it as consisting of “all kinds of crooked characters disposed in columns.” It included “crosses and flourishes” and characters from “various alphabets.” In Anthon’s later account he described characters from Hebrew and Greek. On Martin’s report Anthon had said “they were Egyptian, Chaldaic, Assyriac, and Arabic” (JS─H1:64). The characters were “arranged in perpendicular columns, and the whole ended in a rude delineation of a circle divided into various compartments, decked with various strange marks.” Anthon saw in this circular design an echo of “the Mexican Calender given by Humboldt,” meaning the Aztec calendar published by Alexander Von Humboldt in 1814.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2020-03-22/aztec-calendar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Aztec calendar from Alexander von Humboldt, Researches Concerning the Institutions &amp;amp; Monuments of the Ancient Inhabitants of America, 1814, plate XXIII.&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Aztec calendar from Alexander von Humboldt, Researches Concerning the Institutions &amp;amp; Monuments of the Ancient Inhabitants of America, 1814, plate XXIII.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In 1841 Anthon would again describe the paper Harris presented him:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The characters were arranged in columns, like the [C]hinese mode of writing, and presented the most singular medley that I had ever beheld. Greek, Hebrew, and all sorts of letters . . . were intermingled with sundry delineations of half moons, stars, and other natural objects, and the whole ended in a rude representation of the Mexican zodiac. “An informant,” possibly Charles W. Brown, reported to Orsamus Turner that Martin had shown him the facsimile Joseph had drawn, which the informant understood to transcribe the plates’ “title page.” He described it as containing “concentric circles, between, above, and below which were characters, with little resemblance to letters.” This account of a circular symbol on the plates facsimile resembles Anthon’s description of a symbol resembling the Aztec calendar, which consisted of a sun symbol surrounded by concentric circles and divided into symbol-laden compartments by the sun’s rays.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Martin’s Kirtland, Ohio, neighbor and confidant Francis Gladden Bishop, who acquired considerable information from Martin, gave this description in 1850:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;On the last plate . . . is a circle with rays proceeding from it resembling the sun, as commonly sketched, and around this circle are twenty-four circles more, but of a different character from the first, as each of these circles is composed of figures resembling stars, and half-moons—as, a star, then a half-moon, and so continued until the twenty-four circles are complete.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#references&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anthon and his contemporaries couldn’t have translated Egyptian, let alone reformed Egyptian, because the Rosetta Stone had not yet unlocked the key to translating Egyptian hieroglyphics. This served as evidence to Harris that Smith was more gifted than the scholars and linguists. When Smith translated the title page, coinciding with 2 Nephi 26 as shown above, he retrofitted a prophecy of the encounter between Harris and Anthon in 2 Nephi 27 to make it look like it was a fulfillment of prophecy from the biblical passage in Isaiah 29. The plagiarism of Isaiah 29 and Smith’s attempt to modernize it into a fulfilled prophecy will be deconstructed further at a later time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reformed-egyptian-or-deformed-english&quot;&gt;REFORMED EGYPTIAN OR DEFORMED ENGLISH&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the facsimile that Harris showed Professor Anthon is lost we do have a portion of the characters that Smith claimed were reformed Egyptian. The ‘Caractors’ document is the closest we can get to seeing what Smith claimed were the reformed Egyptian hieroglyphics found on the golden plates and can be viewed on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.josephsmithpapers.org/paper-summary/appendix-2-document-1-characters-copied-by-john-whitmer-circa-1829-1831/1%23historical-intro&quot;&gt;Joseph Smith Paper’s Project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Instead of ”Re-formed Egyptian” many of the “Caractors” are deformed English, as any one will observe who will compare them with English letters, figures and signs.”&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#references&quot;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2020-03-22/caracters-deformed-english.png&quot; alt=&quot;https://www.missedinsunday.com/memes/scripture/caractors/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These characters have been examined in great depth by historian Dan Vogel which can be viewed on YouTube: &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/aMPFKZ2E4MM&quot;&gt;https://youtu.be/aMPFKZ2E4MM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title-page-commentary&quot;&gt;TITLE PAGE COMMENTARY&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The title page can be overwhelming to a new reader of the text. Some commentary on the title page will be somewhat helpful in understanding this sometimes complex book of scripture:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;an abridgment of the record of the people of Nephi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “people of Nephi” refer to the Nephites who were primarily the righteous peoples in the Book of Mormon and set apart from other groups by their advanced warfare, white and delightsome skin color, and having a knowledge of Christianity 600 years before Christ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;written to the Lamanites… and… Jew and Gentile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lamanites are &lt;del&gt;the principal&lt;/del&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#references&quot;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; among the ancestors of the American Indians. According to the book, the white skinned Nephites were destroyed because of their wickedness by the cursed dark-skinned Lamanites 400 years after the coming of Christ. Moroni was the last Nephite who completed the abridgment and buried the golden book close to Smith’s property on a hill that was used by the glass lookers to find buried treasure. The destruction of the Nephites left the Native Americans devoid of any knowledge of Jesus Christ. The Book of Mormon, according to the author, was written to bring the message of Christianity to these ancient mound builders while also settling the debates prevalent in 19th-century religious revivals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;written and sealed and hid up unto the Lord&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Noah Webster’s 1828 dictionary, to “seal up” the book means simply “to inclose; to hide; to conceal” or “to keep secret.”&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#references&quot;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Smith may have used the word seal to refer to the circular pattern of the facsimile he produced for Harris as the last leaf in the golden bible similar to the Great Seal of the United States on the back of a dollar or Turkish travel certificates that resemble Anthon’s description of the characters document in having circular symbols (seals) and representations of moons and stars.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#references&quot;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;come forth by the gift and power of God&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gold plates were translated by the gift and power of God according to Smith. Smith did not leave much commentary on the translation process perhaps to distance himself from the controversial means of how the book came forth (using his chocolate colored peep stone by placing it in his white stonepipe hat and dictated to a scribe).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;to come forth in due time by the way of Gentile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smith dictated several prophecies about himself in the Book of Mormon, Doctrine &amp;amp; Covenants, and the Joseph Smith revision or translation of the King James Version of the Bible. Joseph Smith was the gentile to bring forth the translation of the ancient record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;An abridgment…of the people of Jared&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Book of Mormon forces the orthodox believer into many literal interpretations of the Bible, including the confounding of all languages at the Tower of Babel. The “people of Jared” or “Jaredites” supposedly migrated from this tower to the New World using unknown dish-like barge technology in a 344 day journey without their language being confounded at the tower. The Jaredites arrived in the Americas in ~2,200 BC and their civilization came to an end in ~600 BC in an epic final battle in which the two opposing kings fought until king Coriantumr cut off king Shiz’s head who then died after one headless last-breath push-up.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#references&quot;&gt;14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;convincing…that Jesus is the Christ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Smith published The Book of Mormon it settled the mound builder myth, attempted at settling differences of opinions in regards to the Bible and silence Deism and the rise of Thomas Paine’s book, The Age of Reason. Smith, in this regard, can be viewed as trying to bring understanding to the confusing religious world as it provided answers to the question of how native Americans fit into the story of Christianity. The book was written partially to convince the native Americans, who were viewed as the Lamanites, of the covenants of the Lord and converting them to Christianity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;the mistake of men: wherefore condemn not the things of God&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author of the title page seemed concerned that the book would be rejected if mistakes were found and there have been thousands of grammatical mistakes in the text. Joseph claimed the book was “the most correct of any book on earth” and apologists would quickly make an argument that he was referring to doctrine and not grammatical errors. As we continue our deep dive into the Book of Mormon we will examine some of these mistakes and allow the reader to determine for themselves if the mistakes are only grammatical or are more problematic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;guide-to-book-of-mormon-groups&quot;&gt;GUIDE TO BOOK OF MORMON GROUPS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are having a hard time remembering who the Nephites, Lamanites, Jaredites and Gentiles refer to perhaps this graphic will come in handy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2020-03-22/bom-peoples.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;https://www.missedinsunday.com/memes/scripture/caractors/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;REFERENCES&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Holland, Jeffrey R. “Safety for the Soul.” &lt;em&gt;The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-Day Saints&lt;/em&gt;, Oct. 2009, https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/general-conference/2009/10/safety-for-the-soul.p19#p19&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Smith, J. (1829) Title page for The Book of Mormon: an account written by the hand of Mormon upon plates taken from the plates of Nephi … by Joseph Smith, Junior, author and proprietor. [Pdf] Retrieved from the Library of Congress, https://www.loc.gov/item/2016660778/.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mormon 9:32. Book of Mormon. https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/morm/9.p32#p32&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;History of the Church, 1:71&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oliver Cowdery to W. W. Phelps, 7 Sept. 1834, [Letter I], Latter Day Saints’ Messenger and Advocate 1 (Oct. 1834) &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikisource.org/wiki/Latter_Day_Saints%27_Messenger_and_Advocate/Volume_1/Number_1&quot;&gt;https://en.wikisource.org/wiki/Latter_Day_Saints%27_Messenger_and_Advocate/Volume_1/Number_1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;David Whitmer, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.utlm.org/onlinebooks/address1.htm&quot;&gt;“An Address to All Believers in Christ”&lt;/a&gt; (1887), 12; Quinn (1998, p. 172).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Daniel H. Ludlow, “The Title Page,” in &lt;em&gt;First Nephi, The Doctrinal Foundation&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Monte S. Nyman and Charles D. Tate Jr. (Provo, UT: Religious Studies Center, Brigham Young University, 1988), 19–34. https://rsc.byu.edu/book-mormon-first-nephi-doctrinal-foundation/title-page&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vogel, D. (2004). Jacob and Nephi, Disciples of Isaiah. In &lt;em&gt;Joseph Smith: The Making of a Prophet&lt;/em&gt;. Signature Books.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bradley, Don. The Lost 116 Pages: Reconstructing the Book of Mormon’s Missing Stories (pp. 20-25). Greg Kofford Books.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Cumorah revisited”, Charles A. Shook, 1910 – &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/cumorahrevisited00shoo&quot;&gt;https://archive.org/details/cumorahrevisited00shoo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fletcher Stack, Peggy. “Single Word Change in Book of Mormon Speaks Volumes.” The Salt Lake Tribune, 8 Nov. 2007, archive.sltrib.com/article.php?id=7403990&amp;amp;itype=NGPSID.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Noah Webster, An American Dictionary of the English Language, s.v. “seal.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bradley, Don. The Lost 116 Pages: Reconstructing the Book of Mormon’s Missing Stories (p. 24). Greg Kofford Books. Kindle Edition.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ether 15 Book of Mormon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;H&lt;/span&gt;ello, friends! This is the first post in an ongoing series of what will be an in-depth analysis of the Book of Mormon. The Book of Mormon—whether you believe it is divine and historical or a 19th-century work of pseudepigrapha—has deeply influenced millions of people. I have read and studied this book over thirty times in my life. Now I will be studying it from a new perspective because I have changed my position from a true believing member of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints to a disbeliever. I now view the Book of Mormon as non-historical 19th-century Bible fan fiction fabricated by Joseph Smith.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://NotYourMothersMormonism.com/blog/bom-title-page/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://NotYourMothersMormonism.com/blog/bom-title-page/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Wives of Joseph Smith</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The 34 wives of Joseph Smith haven’t received the attention in Mormon history they deserve. The following paintings of Smith’s wives were done by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/08/18/us/mormon-leader-joseph-smiths-34-wives-inspire-utah-artist.html&quot;&gt;Leslie O. Peterson&lt;/a&gt;. The personal histories or each wife can be found in each link below the paintings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;emma-smith&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Emma Smith&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-01_Emma-Smith.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Emma Smith — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Emma Hale Smith Bidamon was the first wife of Joseph Smith and a leader in the early days of the Latter Day Saint movement, both during Joseph’s lifetime and afterward as a member of the Reorganized Church of Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/prelude-emma-smith-part-two/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/prelude-emma-smith-part-two/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fanny-alger&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Fanny Alger&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-02_Fanny-Alger.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Fanny Alger — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Frances Ward (“Fanny”) Alger Custer (September 30, 1816 – November 29, 1889) was possibly the first plural wife of Joseph Smith, the founder of the Latter Day Saint movement, although scholars have disagreed about whether Smith’s relationship with Alger was an early plural marriage or simply a sexual indiscretion.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fanny_Alger&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fanny_Alger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lucinda-morgan-harris&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Lucinda Morgan Harris&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-03_Lucinda-Morgan-Harris.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Lucinda Morgan Harris — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Even before her association with Joseph Smith, this woman had a story to tell. She was married to a famous Anti-Masonic martyr, a notable character in Nauvoo and also to the Mormon prophet Joseph Smith at age 37. She was also a mother, an early pioneer and frontierswoman, and left it all behind to become a Catholic nun and serve in the Civil War.” - Lindsay Hansen Park&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-lucinda-morgan-harris-episode-02/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-lucinda-morgan-harris-episode-02/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;louisa-beaman&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Louisa Beaman&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-04_Louisa-Beaman.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Louisa Beaman — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The first recognized sealing in Nauvoo was that of Louisa Beaman to Joseph Smith by Joseph Noble in 1841. For many years, Louisa was considered the first ‘official’ plural wife of Joseph Smith.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-louisa-beaman-episode-03/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-louisa-beaman-episode-03/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;zina-huntington-jacobs-young-smith&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Zina Huntington Jacobs Young Smith&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-05_Zina-Huntington-Jacobs-Young-Smith.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Zina Huntington Jacobs Young Smith — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Husband was Henry Bailey Jacobs, who was aware of her plural marriage to Smith. Jacobs wrote, “Whatever the Prophet did was right, without making the wisdom of God’s authorities bend to the reasoning of any man.” Sister of Presendia Huntington. After Smith’s death, married Brigham Young while husband Jacobs was on mission to England.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-zina-huntington-jacobs-young-smith-episode-04/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-zina-huntington-jacobs-young-smith-episode-04/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;presendia-huntington-buell&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Presendia Huntington Buell&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-06_Presendia-Huntington-Buell.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Presendia Huntington Buell — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(September 7, 1810 in Watertown, New York – February 1, 1892 in Salt Lake City, Utah Territory). Sister of Zina. After Smith’s death, married Heber C. Kimball.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-presendia-huntington-buell-episdoe-05/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-presendia-huntington-buell-episdoe-05/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;agnes-coolbrith&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Agnes Coolbrith&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-07_Agnes-Coolbrith.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Agnes Coolbrith — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In spite of Agnes’ husband Don Carlos Smith’s opposition to the practice… Agnes would marry Joseph Smith, allegedly as an Old Testament marriage (where the brother married another brother’s widow). The marriage was guarded with secrecy. On January 6, 1842 Brigham Young wrote a cryptic entry in his journal using Masonic symbols. Decoded, it reads: “I was taken in to the lodge J Smith was Agness”. The abbreviation “was” means “wedded and sealed”.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-agnes-coolbrith-episode-06/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-agnes-coolbrith-episode-06/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sylvia-sessions&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Sylvia Sessions&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-08_Sylvia-Sessions.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Sylvia Sessions — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There is some debate over the exact date Sylvia was sealed to Joseph Smith, but most sources agree that it was some time around February 8, 1843, which was around the time when Windsor was excommunicated for suing a fellow member in civil court over money that was owed to him. There is some debate whether Sylvia’s marriage to Jospeh was before or after Windsor’s excommunication, and whether Sylvia and Windsor separated for some period during that time. Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.feministmormonhousewives.org/2011/09/sylvia-session-remembering-the-forgotten-women-of-joseph-smith/&quot;&gt;http://www.feministmormonhousewives.org/2011/09/sylvia-session-remembering-the-forgotten-women-of-joseph-smith/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;patty-sessions&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Patty Sessions&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-09_Patty-Sessions.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Patty Sessions — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Patty’s daughter Sylvia was married to Joseph Smith. It’s not clear whether Patty knew of the marriage, but it’s likely she did, or found out soon after, since she herself was married to Joseph a month later. Patty wrote in her journal: I was sealed to Joseph Smith by Willard Richards March 9, 1842 in Newel K Whitney’s chamber Nauvoo, for Eternity…Sylvia was presant when I was sealed to Joseph Smith. Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-patty-sessions-episode-08/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-patty-sessions-episode-08/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mary-elizabeth-rollins-lightner&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Mary Elizabeth Rollins Lightner&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-10_Mary-Elizabeth-Rollins-Lightner.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Mary Elizabeth Rollins Lightner — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Mary wrote, “Joseph Smith told me about his great vision concerning me. He said I was the first woman God commanded him to take as a plural wife.” In the fall of that year, Mary and her family left Kirtland for “Zion”, which was being established in Missouri. Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-mary-elizabeth-rollins-lightner-episode-09/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-mary-elizabeth-rollins-lightner-episode-09/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;marinda-nancy-johnson-hyde&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Marinda Nancy Johnson Hyde&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-11_Marinda-Nancy-Johnson-Hyde.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Marinda Nancy-Johnson-Hyde — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“On the 3d month, 27th, 1849, William Arrowsmith of August, Lee county, Iowa, about sixteen miles from Nauvoo… He never was a Mormon, but he married the sister of the Mormon apostle John Taylor. The Mormons persuaded his wife to leave him and they robbed him of 100 dollars worth of property. He says… that he, William Arrowsmith, slept at his mother-in-law’s, who was a Mormon, when Joseph Smith slept with Orson Hyde’s wife, under the same roof.“ - John Bowes Painting by Leslie O. Peterson&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-marinda-nancy-johnson-hyde-episode-11/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-marinda-nancy-johnson-hyde-episode-11/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;elizabeth-davis-durfee&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Elizabeth Davis Durfee&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-12_Elizabeth-Davis-Durfee.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Elizabeth Davis-Durfee — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Elizabeth was said to be a good friend of Emma Smith’s, although it is most likely Emma did not know of the marriage… Elizabeth and Emma Smith also had the famous conversation, reported through Zina Huntington where Elizabeth asked Emma if she believed Joseph Smith was a prophet of God and Emma answered, “Yes. But I wish to God I did not know it.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-elizabeth-davis-durfee-episode-12/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-elizabeth-davis-durfee-episode-12/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sarah-kingsley-cleveland&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Sarah Kingsley Cleveland&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-13_Sarah-Kingsley-Cleveland.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Sarah Kingsley Cleveland — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Sarah Marietta Kingsley Cleveland was the first counselor to Emma Smith in the presidency of the Relief Society from 1842 to 1844. Cleveland was born in Becket, Berkshire County, Massachusetts to Ebenezer Kingsley. She was married to John Cleveland and later to the Mormon prophet Joseph Smith.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-sarah-kingsley-cleveland-episode-13/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-sarah-kingsley-cleveland-episode-13/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;delcena-johnson-sherman&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Delcena Johnson Sherman&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-14_Delcena-Johnson-Sherman.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Delcena Johnson-Sherman — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Delcena’s brother Benjamin left for Canada on a mission. He returned in July of 1842. He later wrote, “The marriage of my Eldest Sister to the Prophet [Joseph Smith] was before my Return to Nauvoo. and it being…admitted I asked no questions.” In Nauvoo, Delcena was living with another one of Joseph’s wives, Louisa Beaman. Less than a year later, Benjamin, Delcena and Louisa would be influential in introducing Delcena’s younger sister, Almera, to plural marriage… Painting by Leslie O. Peterson&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-delcena-johnson-sherman-episode-14/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-delcena-johnson-sherman-episode-14/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;almera-johnson&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Almera Johnson&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-15_Almera-Johnson.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Almera Johnson — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hyrum Smith… turned to Almera and said, “I know that Joseph was comanded to take more wives and he waited Untill an Angel with drawn Sword Stood before him and declared that if [he] longer delayed fulfilling that command he would Slay him… [Hyrum] came to me and said I need not be afraid. I had been fearing and doubting about the principle and so had he, but he now knew it was true. After this time I lived with the Prophet Joseph as his wife.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-almera-johnson-episode-23/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-almera-johnson-episode-23/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;eliza-r-snow&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Eliza R. Snow&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-16_Eliza-R.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Eliza R. Snow — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Todd Compton calls her the “Childless Mother of Mothers in Israel.” Brigham Young called her ‘Priestess, Prophetess, and Presidentess.’ We know of her as a pioneer, an early president of the Relief Society, president of Deseret Hospital, president of the Women’s Department of the Endowment House, and an author. She is considered one of the great women in Mormon history. Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/uncategorized/year-of-polygamy-eliza-r-snow-episode-15/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/uncategorized/year-of-polygamy-eliza-r-snow-episode-15/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sarah-ann-whitney&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Sarah Ann Whitney&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-17_Sarah-Ann-Whitney.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Sarah Ann Whitney — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Sarah’s mother Elizabeth wrote: “He [Joseph Smith] had been strictly charge by the angel… that the most profound secrecy must be maintained… He… confided to him [Newel] the principles [of polygamy]… My husband revealed these things to me… We pondered upon them… Our hearts were comforted and… we were willing to give our eldest daughter, then only seventeen years of age, to Joseph, in the hold order of plural marriage.” Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-sarah-ann-whitney-episode-16/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-sarah-ann-whitney-episode-16/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;martha-mcbride-knight&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Martha McBride Knight&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-18_Martha-McBride-Knight.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Martha McBride Knight — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Less than a month after Martha’s first husband Vinson’s death, Martha married Joseph Smith with Heber C. Kimball performing the ceremony. Shortly after, her five-year-old daughter passed away from the measles. Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-martha-mcbride-knight-episode-17/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-martha-mcbride-knight-episode-17/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ruth-vose-sayers&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Ruth Vose Sayers&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-19_Ruth-Vose-Sayers.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Ruth Vose Sayers — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For whatever reason and circumstances, in February 1843, Ruth married Joseph Smith in a secret ceremony but continued to live with [her husband] Edward (according to her 1869 affidavit). Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.feministmormonhousewives.org/2011/12/remembering-the-forgotten-women-of-joseph-smith-ruth-daggettt-vose-sayers-smith/&quot;&gt;http://www.feministmormonhousewives.org/2011/12/remembering-the-forgotten-women-of-joseph-smith-ruth-daggettt-vose-sayers-smith/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;flora-ann-woodworth&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Flora Ann Woodworth&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-20_Flora-Ann-Woodworth.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Flora Ann Woodworth — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Helen Mar attended to [Flora while sick] and said, “until she recovered her strength, she had lain helpless for many days, and her heavy raven locks were so matted together that it took me hours to comb them out.” Helen Mar once again records, “Flora…had been very sick, but is now slowly gaining her health. [She felt] condemned [for marrying a non-Mormon and] made this confession to me while I was nursing her, and said she desired to cling to Joseph hereafter.” Painting by Leslie O. Peterson&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-flora-ann-woodworth-episode-19/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-flora-ann-woodworth-episode-19/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;eliza-maria-patridge-lyman&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Eliza Maria Patridge Lyman&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-21_Eliza-Maria-Patridge-Lyman.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Eliza Maria Patridge Lyman — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Eliza: “After a time, my sister Emily and myself went to live in the family of the Prophet Joseph Smith… While there, he taught to us the plan of celestial marriage and asked us to enter into that order with him. This was truly a great trial for me but I had the most implicit confidence in him as a Prophet of the Lord and not but believe his words and as a matter of course accept of the privilege of being sealed to him as a wife for time and all eternity. We were sealed in 1843 by H. C. K…”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-eliza-partridge-episode-22/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-eliza-partridge-episode-22/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;emily-patridge&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Emily Patridge&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-22_Emily-Patridge.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Emily Patridge — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Emily: “She [Elizabeth Durfee] introduced the subject of spiritual wives as they called it in that day. She wondered if there was any truth in the report she heard. I thought I could tell her something that would make her open her eyes if I chose, but I did not choose to. I kept my own council and said nothing.” Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-emily-partridge-episode-20/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-emily-partridge-episode-20/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lucy-walker&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Lucy Walker&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-23_Lucy-Walker.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Lucy Walker — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Joseph warned Lucy to keep the marriage secret, and promised that he would someday acknowledge her as his wife, “beyond the Rocky Mountains”. He then gave Lucy an ominous ultimatum, “It is a command of God to you. I will give you untill to-morrow to decide this matter. If you reject this message the gate will be closed forever against you.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-lucy-walker-episode-24/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-lucy-walker-episode-24/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sarah-lawrence&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Sarah Lawrence&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-24_Sarah-Lawrence.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Sarah Lawrence — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the spring of 1843, Joseph married Sarah and Maria [Lawrence], and were some of the few marriages that Emma Smith had apparently given her permission to.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-the-lawrence-sisters-episode-25/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-the-lawrence-sisters-episode-25/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;maria-lawrence&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Maria Lawrence&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-25_Maria-Lawrence.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Maria Lawrence — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the spring of 1843, Joseph married Sarah and Maria [Lawrence], and were some of the few marriages that Emma Smith had apparently given her permission to.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-the-lawrence-sisters-episode-25/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-the-lawrence-sisters-episode-25/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;helen-mar-kimball&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Helen Mar Kimball&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-26_Helen-Mar-Kimball.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Helen Mar Kimball — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the spring of 1843, when Helen was 14 years old, her father described the doctrine of plural marriage to her. He asked if she would consent to be “sealed to Joseph”. Helen described her reaction: My father was the first to introduce it to me, which had a similar effect to a sudden shock of a small earthquake. When he found (after the first outburst of displeasure for supposed injury) that I received it meekly, he took the first opportunity to introduce Sarah Ann to me as Joseph’s wife&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Helen_Mar_Kimball&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Helen_Mar_Kimball&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hannah-ells&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Hannah Ells&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-27_Hannah-Ells.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Hannah Ells — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;According to LDS Church Historian Andrew Jenson, Hannah married Joseph Smith some time before the summer of 1843. During her time in Nauvoo, Hannah lived in the home of John Benbow and perhaps with her brother Josiah for a time. John Benbow writes, “President Smith frequently visited his wife Hannah at [my] house.” It was only a little over a year of being married to Joseph that he was martyred and she became a widow.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-hannah-ells-episode-27/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-hannah-ells-episode-27/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;elvira-cowles-holmes&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Elvira Cowles Holmes&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-28_Elvira-Cowles-Holmes.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Elvira Cowles Holmes — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;On June 1, 1843, six months after her marriage to Jonathan, Elvira was sealed to Joseph Smith… By 1846 [Jonathon] stood proxy as Elvira was sealed to Joseph for eternity. Jonathan would be sealed to Elvira for time, but she would be Joseph’s for eternity… This meant that Jonathan an Elvira’s children would become Joseph’s in the eternities. This apparently weighed heavily on Jonathan’s mind…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-elvira-cowles-holmes-episode-28/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-elvira-cowles-holmes-episode-28/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rhoda-richards&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Rhoda Richards&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-29_Rhoda-Richards.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Rhoda Richards — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;On June 12 1843, Rhoda married Joseph Smith. Her brother Willard performed the marriage. Rhoda wrote, “In my young days I buried my first and only love, and true to that affiance [pledge], I have passed companionless through life; but am sure of having my proper place and standing in the resurrection, having been sealed to the prophet Joseph, according to the celestial law, by his own request, under the inspiration of divine revelation.” Rhoda now became Joseph’s approximate twenty-eighth wife.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-rhoda-richards-episode-29/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-rhoda-richards-episode-29/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;desdemona-wadsworth-fullmer&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Desdemona Wadsworth Fullmer&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-30_Desdemona-Wadsworth-Fullmer.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Desdemona Wadsworth Fullmer — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Desdemona married Joseph Smith in July of 1843. As Joseph continued to secretly accumulate wives, his first wife, Emma, struggled with polygamy. Perhaps Desdemona experienced, or maybe only feared, the anguish of Emma discovering her and Joseph’s relationship. She recalls the resultant anxiety, “In the rise of poligamy i was warned in a dream Amy [Emma] Smith was going to poisen me.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wivesofjosephsmith.org/30-DesdemonaFullmer.htm&quot;&gt;http://wivesofjosephsmith.org/30-DesdemonaFullmer.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;olive-grey-frost&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Olive Grey Frost&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-31_Olive-Grey-Frost.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Olive Grey Frost — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A member of the church, Joseph E. Robinson said, “During the afternoon I called on Aunt Lizzie… she knew Joseph Smith had more than two wives. Said he married… Olive Frost [and] had a child by him and that both died.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-olive-grey-frost-episode-30/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-olive-grey-frost-episode-30/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;melissa-lott&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Melissa Lott&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-32_Melissa-Lott.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Melissa Lott — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;On the same day that Melissa married Joseph, her parents, Cornelius and Permelia, were sealed together for eternity. As with the parents Sarah Ann Whitney, and Helen Mar Kimball, perhaps this was a reward for giving their daughter to Joseph in marriage.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wivesofjosephsmith.org/32-MelissaLott.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.wivesofjosephsmith.org/32-MelissaLott.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nancy-winchester&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Nancy Winchester&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-33_Nancy-Winchester.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Nancy Winchester — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Very little is know about her marriage to Joseph Smith, but LDS Church Historian Andrew Jenson records Nancy as a wife, marrying sometime before Joseph’s death. The marriage is mostly likely a dynastic union, and one can only speculate on the marriage since such little evidence is provided. Nancy would have been fourteen or fifteen years old at the time of the marriage.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-nancy-winchester-episode-33/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-nancy-winchester-episode-33/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fanny-young&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Fanny Young&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/js-wives/Wife-34_Fanny-Young.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Fanny Young — Painting by Leslie O. Peterson. 2015.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Brigham Young recalled the fall of 1843 when he, Joseph Smith and Fanny were discussing the Mormon belief in the necessity of entering plural marriage in order to obtain exaltation and enter the celestial kingdom. Unimpressed with the doctrine, Fanny was to have said, “Now, don’t talk to me; when I get into the celestial kingdom, if I ever get there, I shall request the privilege of being a ministering angel; that is the labor I wish to perform. I don’t want any companion in that world…”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-fanny-young-episode-34/&quot;&gt;https://www.yearofpolygamy.com/year-of-polygamy/year-of-polygamy-fanny-young-episode-34/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The 34 wives of Joseph Smith haven’t received the attention in Mormon history they deserve. The following paintings of Smith’s wives were done by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/08/18/us/mormon-leader-joseph-smiths-34-wives-inspire-utah-artist.html&quot;&gt;Leslie O. Peterson&lt;/a&gt;. The personal histories or each wife can be found in each link below the paintings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://NotYourMothersMormonism.com/blog/joseph-smith-wives/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://NotYourMothersMormonism.com/blog/joseph-smith-wives/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Mormon Memorization Madness</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;W&lt;/span&gt;hen I was a missionary in the California, Roseville mission for The Church
of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints I spent many hours memorizing scripture. My mission president Danel Bachman was a 
Mormon scholar and influenced the time I spent studying the history, doctrine and scripture of the Mormon church. I had
hundreds of 3x5 cards to assist me in memorizing scripture but I lost them over the years. Here are the majority of scripture
I had or still have memorized:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#old-testament&quot;&gt;Old Testament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#new-testament&quot;&gt;New Testament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#book-of-mormon&quot;&gt;Book of Mormon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#doctrine--covenants&quot;&gt;Doctrine &amp;amp; Covenants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#pearl-of-great-price&quot;&gt;Pearl of Great Price&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot; id=&quot;old-testament&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Old Testament&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;genesis-126-27&quot;&gt;Genesis 1:26-27&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;26&lt;/strong&gt; And God said, Let us make man in our image, after our likeness: and let them have dominion over the fish of the sea, and over the fowl of the air, and over the cattle, and over all the earth, and over every creeping thing that creepeth upon the earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;27&lt;/strong&gt; So God created man in his own image, in the image of God created he him; male and female created he them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;job-1925-26&quot;&gt;Job 19:25-26&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25&lt;/strong&gt; For I know that my redeemer liveth, and that he shall stand at the latter day upon the earth:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;26&lt;/strong&gt; And though after my skin worms destroy this body, yet in my flesh shall I see God:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;isaiah-118&quot;&gt;Isaiah 1:18&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18&lt;/strong&gt; Come now, and let us reason together, saith the Lord: though your sins be as scarlet, they shall be as white as snow; though they be red like crimson, they shall be as wool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;isaiah-245&quot;&gt;Isaiah 24:5&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; The earth also is defiled under the inhabitants thereof; because they have transgressed the laws, changed the ordinance, broken the everlasting covenant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;isaiah-2911-14&quot;&gt;Isaiah 29:11-14&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11&lt;/strong&gt; And the vision of all is become unto you as the words of a book that is sealed, which men deliver to one that is learned, saying, Read this, I pray thee: and he saith, I cannot; for it is sealed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt; And the book is delivered to him that is not learned, saying, Read this, I pray thee: and he saith, I am not learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13&lt;/strong&gt; Wherefore the Lord said, Forasmuch as this people draw near me with their mouth, and with their lips do honour me, but have removed their heart far from me, and their fear toward me is taught by the precept of men:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14&lt;/strong&gt; Therefore, behold, I will proceed to do a marvellous work among this people, even a marvellous work and a wonder: for the wisdom of their wise men shall perish, and the understanding of their prudent men shall be hid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;isaiah-558-9&quot;&gt;Isaiah 55:8-9&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; For my thoughts are not your thoughts, neither are your ways my ways, saith the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt; For as the heavens are higher than the earth, so are my ways higher than your ways, and my thoughts than your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;jeremiah-14-9&quot;&gt;Jeremiah 1:4-9&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; Then the word of the Lord came unto me, saying,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; Before I formed thee in the belly I knew thee; and before thou camest forth out of the womb I sanctified thee, and I ordained thee a prophet unto the nations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; Then said I, Ah, Lord God! behold, I cannot speak: for I am a child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; But the Lord said unto me, Say not, I am a child: for thou shalt go to all that I shall send thee, and whatsoever I command thee thou shalt speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; Be not afraid of their faces: for I am with thee to deliver thee, saith the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt; Then the Lord put forth his hand, and touched my mouth. And the Lord said unto me, Behold, I have put my words in thy mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;ezekiel-3715-17&quot;&gt;Ezekiel 37:15-17&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15&lt;/strong&gt; ¶ The word of the Lord came again unto me, saying,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16&lt;/strong&gt; Moreover, thou son of man, take thee one stick, and write upon it, For Judah, and for the children of Israel his companions: then take another stick, and write upon it, For Joseph, the stick of Ephraim, and for all the house of Israel his companions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt; And join them one to another into one stick; and they shall become one in thine hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;daniel-244-45&quot;&gt;Daniel 2:44-45&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;44&lt;/strong&gt; And in the days of these kings shall the God of heaven set up a kingdom, which shall never be destroyed: and the kingdom shall not be left to other people, but it shall break in pieces and consume all these kingdoms, and it shall stand for ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;45&lt;/strong&gt; Forasmuch as thou sawest that the stone was cut out of the mountain without hands, and that it brake in pieces the iron, the brass, the clay, the silver, and the gold; the great God hath made known to the king what shall come to pass hereafter: and the dream is certain, and the interpretation thereof sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;amos-37&quot;&gt;Amos 3:7&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; Surely the Lord God will do nothing, but he revealeth his secret unto his servants the prophets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;amos-811-12&quot;&gt;Amos 8:11-12&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11&lt;/strong&gt; ¶ Behold, the days come, saith the Lord God, that I will send a famine in the land, not a famine of bread, nor a thirst for water, but of hearing the words of the Lord:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt; And they shall wander from sea to sea, and from the north even to the east, they shall run to and fro to seek the word of the Lord, and shall not find &lt;em&gt;it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot; id=&quot;new-testament&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;New Testament&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;matthew-313-17&quot;&gt;Matthew 3:13-17&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13&lt;/strong&gt; ¶ Then cometh Jesus from Galilee to Jordan unto John, to be baptized of him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14&lt;/strong&gt; But John forbad him, saying, I have need to be baptized of thee, and comest thou to me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15&lt;/strong&gt; And Jesus answering said unto him, Suffer &lt;em&gt;it to be so&lt;/em&gt; now: for thus it becometh us to fulfil all righteousness. Then he suffered him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16&lt;/strong&gt; And Jesus, when he was baptized, went up straightway out of the water: and, lo, the heavens were opened unto him, and he saw the Spirit of God descending like a dove, and lighting upon him:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt; And lo a voice from heaven, saying, This is my beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;matthew-1615-19&quot;&gt;Matthew 16:15-19&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15&lt;/strong&gt; He saith unto them, But whom say ye that I am?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16&lt;/strong&gt; And Simon Peter answered and said, Thou art the Christ, the Son of the living God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt; And Jesus answered and said unto him, Blessed art thou, Simon Bar-jona: for flesh and blood hath not revealed it unto thee, but my Father which is in heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18&lt;/strong&gt; And I say also unto thee, That thou art Peter, and upon this rock I will build my church; and the gates of hell shall not prevail against it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19&lt;/strong&gt; And I will give unto thee the keys of the kingdom of heaven: and whatsoever thou shalt bind on earth shall be bound in heaven: and whatsoever thou shalt loose on earth shall be loosed in heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;matthew-2237-39&quot;&gt;Matthew 22:37-39&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;37&lt;/strong&gt; Jesus said unto him, Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;38&lt;/strong&gt; This is the first and great commandment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;39&lt;/strong&gt; And the second is like unto it, Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;john-31-5&quot;&gt;John 3:1-5&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; There was a man of the Pharisees, named Nicodemus, a ruler of the Jews:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; The same came to Jesus by night, and said unto him, Rabbi, we know that thou art a teacher come from God: for no man can do these miracles that thou doest, except God be with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; Jesus answered and said unto him, Verily, verily, I say unto thee, Except a man be born again, he cannot see the kingdom of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; Nicodemus saith unto him, How can a man be born when he is old? can he enter the second time into his mother’s womb, and be born?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; Jesus answered, Verily, verily, I say unto thee, Except a man be born of water and of the Spirit, he cannot enter into the kingdom of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;john-316-17&quot;&gt;John 3:16-17&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16&lt;/strong&gt; ¶ For God so loved the world, that he gave his only begotten Son, that whosoever believeth in him should not perish, but have everlasting life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt; For God sent not his Son into the world to condemn the world; but that the world through him might be saved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;john-717&quot;&gt;John 7:17&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt; If any man will do his will, he shall know of the doctrine, whether it be of God, or whether I speak of myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;john-1016&quot;&gt;John 10:16&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16&lt;/strong&gt; And other sheep I have, which are not of this fold: them also I must bring, and they shall hear my voice; and there shall be one fold, and one shepherd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;john-1415&quot;&gt;John 14:15&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15&lt;/strong&gt; If ye love me, keep my commandments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;john-146-9&quot;&gt;John 14:6-9&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; Jesus saith unto him, I am the way, the truth, and the life: no man cometh unto the Father, but by me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; If ye had known me, ye should have known my Father also: and from henceforth ye know him, and have seen him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; Philip saith unto him, Lord, shew us the Father, and it sufficeth us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt; Jesus saith unto him, Have I been so long time with you, and yet hast thou not known me, Philip? he that hath seen me hath seen the Father; and how sayest thou then, Shew us the Father?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;john-1426&quot;&gt;John 14:26&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;26&lt;/strong&gt; But the Comforter, which is the Holy Ghost, whom the Father will send in my name, he shall teach you all things, and bring all things to your remembrance, whatsoever I have said unto you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;john-1513-14&quot;&gt;John 15:13-14&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13&lt;/strong&gt; Greater love hath no man than this, that a man lay down his life for his friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14&lt;/strong&gt; Ye are my friends, if ye do whatsoever I command you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;john-173&quot;&gt;John 17:3&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; And this is life eternal, that they might know thee the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom thou hast sent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;acts-238&quot;&gt;Acts 2:38&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;38&lt;/strong&gt; Then Peter said unto them, Repent, and be baptized every one of you in the name of Jesus Christ for the remission of sins, and ye shall receive the gift of the Holy Ghost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;acts-319-21&quot;&gt;Acts 3:19-21&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19&lt;/strong&gt; ¶ Repent ye therefore, and be converted, that your sins may be blotted out, when the times of refreshing shall come from the presence of the Lord;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20&lt;/strong&gt; And he shall send Jesus Christ, which before was preached unto you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21&lt;/strong&gt; Whom the heaven must receive until the times of restitution of all things, which God hath spoken by the mouth of all his holy prophets since the world began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;acts-755-56&quot;&gt;Acts 7:55-56&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;55&lt;/strong&gt; But he, being full of the Holy Ghost, looked up steadfastly into heaven, and saw the glory of God, and Jesus standing on the right hand of God,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;56&lt;/strong&gt; And said, Behold, I see the heavens opened, and the Son of man standing on the right hand of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;acts-2028-30&quot;&gt;Acts 20:28-30&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;28&lt;/strong&gt; ¶ Take heed therefore unto yourselves, and to all the flock, over the which the Holy Ghost hath made you overseers, to feed the church of God, which he hath purchased with his own blood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;29&lt;/strong&gt; For I know this, that after my departing shall grievous wolves enter in among you, not sparing the flock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;30&lt;/strong&gt; Also of your own selves shall men arise, speaking perverse things, to draw away disciples after them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;romans-53-5&quot;&gt;Romans 5:3-5&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; And not only &lt;em&gt;so,&lt;/em&gt; but we glory in tribulations also: knowing that tribulation worketh patience;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; And patience, experience; and experience, hope:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; And hope maketh not ashamed; because the love of God is shed abroad in our hearts by the Holy Ghost which is given unto us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;romans-63-6&quot;&gt;Romans 6:3-6&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; Know ye not, that so many of us as were baptized into Jesus Christ were baptized into his death?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; Therefore we are buried with him by baptism into death: that like as Christ was raised up from the dead by the glory of the Father, even so we also should walk in newness of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; For if we have been planted together in the likeness of his death, we shall be also in the likeness of his resurrection:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; Knowing this, that our old man is crucified with &lt;em&gt;him,&lt;/em&gt; that the body of sin might be destroyed, that henceforth we should not serve sin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;romans-816-17&quot;&gt;Romans 8:16-17&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16&lt;/strong&gt; The Spirit itself beareth witness with our spirit, that we are the children of God:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt; And if children, then heirs; heirs of God, and joint-heirs with Christ; if so be that we suffer with him, that we may be also glorified together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;romans-838-39&quot;&gt;Romans 8:38-39&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;38&lt;/strong&gt; For I am persuaded, that neither death, nor life, nor angels, nor principalities, nor powers, nor things present, nor things to come,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;39&lt;/strong&gt; Nor height, nor depth, nor any other creature, shall be able to separate us from the love of God, which is in Christ Jesus our Lord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;romans-1013-17&quot;&gt;Romans 10:13-17&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13&lt;/strong&gt; For whosoever shall call upon the name of the Lord shall be saved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14&lt;/strong&gt; How then shall they call on him in whom they have not believed? and how shall they believe in him of whom they have not heard? and how shall they hear without a preacher?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15&lt;/strong&gt; And how shall they preach, except they be sent? as it is written, How beautiful are the feet of them that preach the gospel of peace, and bring glad tidings of good things!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16&lt;/strong&gt; But they have not all obeyed the gospel. For Esaias saith, Lord, who hath believed our report?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt; So then faith cometh by hearing, and hearing by the word of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-corinthians-1013&quot;&gt;1 Corinthians 10:13&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13&lt;/strong&gt; There hath no temptation taken you but such as is common to man: but God is faithful, who will not suffer you to be tempted above that ye are able; but will with the temptation also make a way to escape, that ye may be able to bear it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-corinthians-13&quot;&gt;1 Corinthians 13&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; Though I speak with the tongues of men and of angels, and have not charity, I am become as sounding brass, or a tinkling cymbal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; And though I have the gift of prophecy, and understand all mysteries, and all knowledge; and though I have all faith, so that I could remove mountains, and have not charity, I am nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; And though I bestow all my goods to feed the poor, and though I give my body to be burned, and have not charity, it profiteth me nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; Charity suffereth long, and is kind; charity envieth not; charity vaunteth not itself, is not puffed up,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; Doth not behave itself unseemly, seeketh not her own, is not easily provoked, thinketh no evil;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; Rejoiceth not in iniquity, but rejoiceth in the truth;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; Beareth all things, believeth all things, hopeth all things, endureth all things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; Charity never faileth: but whether there be prophecies, they shall fail; whether there be tongues, they shall cease; whether there be knowledge, it shall vanish away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt; For we know in part, and we prophesy in part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; But when that which is perfect is come, then that which is in part shall be done away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11&lt;/strong&gt; When I was a child, I spake as a child, I understood as a child, I thought as a child: but when I became a man, I put away childish things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt; For now we see through a glass, darkly; but then face to face: now I know in part; but then shall I know even as also I am known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13&lt;/strong&gt; And now abideth faith, hope, charity, these three; but the greatest of these is charity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;galatians-16-8&quot;&gt;Galatians 1:6-8&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; Now these things were our examples, to the intent we should not lust after evil things, as they also lusted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; Neither be ye idolaters, as were some of them; as it is written, The people sat down to eat and drink, and rose up to play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; Neither let us commit fornication, as some of them committed, and fell in one day three and twenty thousand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;galatians-522-23&quot;&gt;Galatians 5:22-23&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22&lt;/strong&gt; But the fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, longsuffering, gentleness, goodness, faith,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23&lt;/strong&gt; Meekness, temperance: against such there is no law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;ephesians-110&quot;&gt;Ephesians 1:10&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; That in the dispensation of the fulness of times he might gather together in one all things in Christ, both which are in heaven, and which are on earth; even in him:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;ephesians-219-20&quot;&gt;Ephesians 2:19-20&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19&lt;/strong&gt; Now therefore ye are no more strangers and foreigners, but fellowcitizens with the saints, and of the household of God;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20&lt;/strong&gt; And are built upon the foundation of the apostles and prophets, Jesus Christ himself being the chief corner stone;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;ephesians-411-15&quot;&gt;Ephesians 4:11-15&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11&lt;/strong&gt; And he gave some, apostles; and some, prophets; and some, evangelists; and some, pastors and teachers;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt; For the perfecting of the saints, for the work of the ministry, for the edifying of the body of Christ:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13&lt;/strong&gt; Till we all come in the unity of the faith, and of the knowledge of the Son of God, unto a perfect man, unto the measure of the stature of the fulness of Christ:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14&lt;/strong&gt; That we henceforth be no more children, tossed to and fro, and carried about with every wind of doctrine, by the sleight of men, and cunning craftiness, whereby they lie in wait to deceive;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15&lt;/strong&gt; But speaking the truth in love, may grow up into him in all things, which is the head, even Christ:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-thessalonians-21-4&quot;&gt;2 Thessalonians 2:1-4&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; Now we beseech you, brethren, by the coming of our Lord Jesus Christ, and by our gathering together unto him,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; That ye be not soon shaken in mind, or be troubled, neither by spirit, nor by word, nor by letter as from us, as that the day of Christ is at hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; Let no man deceive you by any means: for that day shall not come, except there come a falling away first, and that man of sin be revealed, the son of perdition;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; Who opposeth and exalteth himself above all that is called God, or that is worshipped; so that he as God sitteth in the temple of God, shewing himself that he is God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-timothy-41-3&quot;&gt;1 Timothy 4:1-3&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; Now the Spirit speaketh expressly, that in the latter times some shall depart from the faith, giving heed to seducing spirits, and doctrines of devils;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; Speaking lies in hypocrisy; having their conscience seared with a hot iron;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; Forbidding to marry, and commanding to abstain from meats, which God hath created to be received with thanksgiving of them which believe and know the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-timothy-31-7&quot;&gt;2 Timothy 3:1-7&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; This know also, that in the last days perilous times shall come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; For men shall be lovers of their own selves, covetous, boasters, proud, blasphemers, disobedient to parents, unthankful, unholy,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; Without natural affection, trucebreakers, false accusers, incontinent, fierce, despisers of those that are good,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; Traitors, heady, highminded, lovers of pleasures more than lovers of God;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; Having a form of godliness, but denying the power thereof: from such turn away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; For of this sort are they which creep into houses, and lead captive silly women laden with sins, led away with divers lusts,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; Ever learning, and never able to come to the knowledge of the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-timothy-43-4&quot;&gt;2 Timothy 4:3-4&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; For the time will come when they will not endure sound doctrine; but after their own lusts shall they heap to themselves teachers, having itching ears;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; And they shall turn away their ears from the truth, and shall be turned unto fables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;hebrews-11-3&quot;&gt;Hebrews 1:1-3&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; God, who at sundry times and in divers manners spake in time past unto the fathers by the prophets,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; Hath in these last days spoken unto us by his Son, whom he hath appointed heir of all things, by whom also he made the worlds;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; Who being the brightness of his glory, and the express image of his person, and upholding all things by the word of his power, when he had by himself purged our sins, sat down on the right hand of the Majesty on high;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;hebrews-54&quot;&gt;Hebrews 5:4&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; And no man taketh this honour unto himself, but he that is called of God, as was Aaron.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;hebrews-116&quot;&gt;Hebrews 11:6&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; But without faith it is impossible to please him: for he that cometh to God must believe that he is, and that he is a rewarder of them that diligently seek him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;hebrews-121-2&quot;&gt;Hebrews 12:1-2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; Wherefore seeing we also are compassed about with so great a cloud of witnesses, let us lay aside every weight, and the sin which doth so easily beset us, and let us run with patience the race that is set before us,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; Looking unto Jesus the author and finisher of our faith; who for the joy that was set before him endured the cross, despising the shame, and is set down at the right hand of the throne of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;hebrews-129&quot;&gt;Hebrews 12:9&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt; Furthermore we have had fathers of our flesh which corrected us, and we gave them reverence: shall we not much rather be in subjection unto the Father of spirits, and live?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;james-15-6&quot;&gt;James 1:5-6&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; If any of you lack wisdom, let him ask of God, that giveth to all men liberally, and upbraideth not; and it shall be given him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; But let him ask in faith, nothing wavering. For he that wavereth is like a wave of the sea driven with the wind and tossed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-peter-21-2&quot;&gt;2 Peter 2:1-2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; But there were false prophets also among the people, even as there shall be false teachers among you, who privily shall bring in damnable heresies, even denying the Lord that bought them, and bring upon themselves swift destruction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; And many shall follow their pernicious ways; by reason of whom the way of truth shall be evil spoken of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-john-32&quot;&gt;1 John 3:2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; Beloved, now are we the sons of God, and it doth not yet appear what we shall be: but we know that, when he shall appear, we shall be like him; for we shall see him as he is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-john-47-9&quot;&gt;1 John 4:7-9&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; Beloved, let us love one another: for love is of God; and every one that loveth is born of God, and knoweth God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; He that loveth not knoweth not God; for God is love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt; In this was manifested the love of God toward us, because that God sent his only begotten Son into the world, that we might live through him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-john-15-7&quot;&gt;1 John 1:5-7&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; This then is the message which we have heard of him, and declare unto you, that God is light, and in him is no darkness at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; If we say that we have fellowship with him, and walk in darkness, we lie, and do not the truth:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; But if we walk in the light, as he is in the light, we have fellowship one with another, and the blood of Jesus Christ his Son cleanseth us from all sin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-john-418-19&quot;&gt;1 John 4:18-19&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18&lt;/strong&gt; There is no fear in love; but perfect love casteth out fear: because fear hath torment. He that feareth is not made perfect in love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19&lt;/strong&gt; We love him, because he first loved us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot; id=&quot;book-of-mormon&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Book of Mormon&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;book-of-mormon-introduction-paragraphs-8-9&quot;&gt;Book of Mormon Introduction Paragraphs 8-9&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We invite all men everywhere to read the Book of Mormon, to ponder in their hearts the message it contains, and then to ask God, the Eternal Father, in the name of Christ if the book is true. Those who pursue this course and ask in faith will gain a testimony of its truth and divinity by the power of the Holy Ghost.
Those who gain this divine witness from the Holy Spirit will also come to know by the same power that Jesus Christ is the Savior of the world, that Joseph Smith is His revelator and prophet in these last days, and that The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is the Lord’s kingdom once again established on the earth, preparatory to the Second Coming of the Messiah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-nephi-37&quot;&gt;1 Nephi 3:7&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; And it came to pass that I, Nephi, said unto my father: I will go and do the things which the Lord hath commanded, for I know that the Lord giveth no commandments unto the children of men, save he shall prepare a way for them that they may accomplish the thing which he commandeth them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-nephi-1736&quot;&gt;1 Nephi 17:36&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;36&lt;/strong&gt; Behold, the Lord hath created the earth that it should be inhabited; and he hath created his children that they should possess it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-nephi-26-9&quot;&gt;2 Nephi 2:6-9&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; Wherefore, redemption cometh in and through the Holy Messiah; for he is full of grace and truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; Behold, he offereth himself a sacrifice for sin, to answer the ends of the law, unto all those who have a broken heart and a contrite spirit; and unto none else can the ends of the law be answered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; Wherefore, how great the importance to make these things known unto the inhabitants of the earth, that they may know that there is no flesh that can dwell in the presence of God, save it be through the merits, and mercy, and grace of the Holy Messiah, who layeth down his life according to the flesh, and taketh it again by the power of the Spirit, that he may bring to pass the resurrection of the dead, being the first that should rise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt; Wherefore, he is the firstfruits unto God, inasmuch as he shall make intercession for all the children of men; and they that believe in him shall be saved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-nephi-227&quot;&gt;2 Nephi 2:27&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;27&lt;/strong&gt; Wherefore, men are free according to the flesh; and all things are given them which are expedient unto man. And they are free to choose liberty and eternal life, through the great Mediator of all men, or to choose captivity and death, according to the captivity and power of the devil; for he seeketh that all men might be miserable like unto himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-nephi-324&quot;&gt;2 Nephi 3:24&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24&lt;/strong&gt; And there shall rise up one mighty among them, who shall do much good, both in word and in deed, being an instrument in the hands of God, with exceeding faith, to work mighty wonders, and do that thing which is great in the sight of God, unto the bringing to pass much restoration unto the house of Israel, and unto the seed of thy brethren.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-nephi-196&quot;&gt;2 Nephi 19:6&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; For unto us a child is born, unto us a son is given; and the government shall be upon his shoulder; and his name shall be called, Wonderful, Counselor, The Mighty God, The Everlasting Father, The Prince of Peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-nephi-252326&quot;&gt;2 Nephi 25:23,26&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23&lt;/strong&gt; For we labor diligently to write, to persuade our children, and also our brethren, to believe in Christ, and to be reconciled to God; for we know that it is by grace that we are saved, after all we can do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;26&lt;/strong&gt; And we talk of Christ, we rejoice in Christ, we preach of Christ, we prophesy of Christ, and we write according to our prophecies, that our children may know to what source they may look for a remission of their sins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-nephi-296-8&quot;&gt;2 Nephi 29:6-8&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; Thou fool, that shall say: A Bible, we have got a Bible, and we need no more Bible. Have ye obtained a Bible save it were by the Jews?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; Know ye not that there are more nations than one? Know ye not that I, the Lord your God, have created all men, and that I remember those who are upon the isles of the sea; and that I rule in the heavens above and in the earth beneath; and I bring forth my word unto the children of men, yea, even upon all the nations of the earth?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; Wherefore murmur ye, because that ye shall receive more of my word? Know ye not that the testimony of two nations is a witness unto you that I am God, that I remember one nation like unto another? Wherefore, I speak the same words unto one nation like unto another. And when the two nations shall run together the testimony of the two nations shall run together also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-nephi-314-7&quot;&gt;2 Nephi 31:4-7&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; Wherefore, I would that ye should remember that I have spoken unto you concerning that prophet which the Lord showed unto me, that should baptize the Lamb of God, which should take away the sins of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; And now, if the Lamb of God, he being holy, should have need to be baptized by water, to fulfil all righteousness, O then, how much more need have we, being unholy, to be baptized, yea, even by water!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; And now, I would ask of you, my beloved brethren, wherein the Lamb of God did fulfil all righteousness in being baptized by water?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; Know ye not that he was holy? But notwithstanding he being holy, he showeth unto the children of men that, according to the flesh he humbleth himself before the Father, and witnesseth unto the Father that he would be obedient unto him in keeping his commandments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-nephi-3113&quot;&gt;2 Nephi 31:13&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13&lt;/strong&gt; Wherefore, my beloved brethren, I know that if ye shall follow the Son, with full purpose of heart, acting no hypocrisy and no deception before God, but with real intent, repenting of your sins, witnessing unto the Father that ye are willing to take upon you the name of Christ, by baptism—yea, by following your Lord and your Savior down into the water, according to his word, behold, then shall ye receive the Holy Ghost; yea, then cometh the baptism of fire and of the Holy Ghost; and then can ye speak with the tongue of angels, and shout praises unto the Holy One of Israel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-nephi-3119-20&quot;&gt;2 Nephi 31:19-20&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19&lt;/strong&gt; And now, my beloved brethren, after ye have gotten into this strait and narrow path, I would ask if all is done? Behold, I say unto you, Nay; for ye have not come thus far save it were by the word of Christ with unshaken faith in him, relying wholly upon the merits of him who is mighty to save.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20&lt;/strong&gt; Wherefore, ye must press forward with a steadfastness in Christ, having a perfect brightness of hope, and a love of God and of all men. Wherefore, if ye shall press forward, feasting upon the word of Christ, and endure to the end, behold, thus saith the Father: Ye shall have eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-nephi-323&quot;&gt;2 Nephi 32:3&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; Angels speak by the power of the Holy Ghost; wherefore, they speak the words of Christ. Wherefore, I said unto you, feast upon the words of Christ; for behold, the words of Christ will tell you all things what ye should do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;jacob-218-19&quot;&gt;Jacob 2:18-19&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18&lt;/strong&gt; But before ye seek for riches, seek ye for the kingdom of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19&lt;/strong&gt; And after ye have obtained a hope in Christ ye shall obtain riches, if ye seek them; and ye will seek them for the intent to do good—to clothe the naked, and to feed the hungry, and to liberate the captive, and administer relief to the sick and the afflicted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;jacob-44-7&quot;&gt;Jacob 4:4-7&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; For, for this intent have we written these things, that they may know that we knew of Christ, and we had a hope of his glory many hundred years before his coming; and not only we ourselves had a hope of his glory, but also all the holy prophets which were before us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; Behold, they believed in Christ and worshiped the Father in his name, and also we worship the Father in his name. And for this intent we keep the law of Moses, it pointing our souls to him; and for this cause it is sanctified unto us for righteousness, even as it was accounted unto Abraham in the wilderness to be obedient unto the commands of God in offering up his son Isaac, which is a similitude of God and his Only Begotten Son.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; Wherefore, we search the prophets, and we have many revelations and the spirit of prophecy; and having all these witnesses we obtain a hope, and our faith becometh unshaken, insomuch that we truly can command in the name of Jesus and the very trees obey us, or the mountains, or the waves of the sea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; Nevertheless, the Lord God showeth us our weakness that we may know that it is by his grace, and his great condescensions unto the children of men, that we have power to do these things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;mosiah-35-10&quot;&gt;Mosiah 3:5-10&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; For behold, the time cometh, and is not far distant, that with power, the Lord Omnipotent who reigneth, who was, and is from all eternity to all eternity, shall come down from heaven among the children of men, and shall dwell in a tabernacle of clay, and shall go forth amongst men, working mighty miracles, such as healing the sick, raising the dead, causing the lame to walk, the blind to receive their sight, and the deaf to hear, and curing all manner of diseases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; And he shall cast out devils, or the evil spirits which dwell in the hearts of the children of men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; And lo, he shall suffer temptations, and pain of body, hunger, thirst, and fatigue, even more than man can suffer, except it be unto death; for behold, blood cometh from every pore, so great shall be his anguish for the wickedness and the abominations of his people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; And he shall be called Jesus Christ, the Son of God, the Father of heaven and earth, the Creator of all things from the beginning; and his mother shall be called Mary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt; And lo, he cometh unto his own, that salvation might come unto the children of men even through faith on his name; and even after all this they shall consider him a man, and say that he hath a devil, and shall scourge him, and shall crucify him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; And he shall rise the third day from the dead; and behold, he standeth to judge the world; and behold, all these things are done that a righteous judgment might come upon the children of men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;mosiah-319&quot;&gt;Mosiah 3:19&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt; And now, my sons, remember, remember that it is upon the rock of our Redeemer, who is Christ, the Son of God, that ye must build your foundation; that when the devil shall send forth his mighty winds, yea, his shafts in the whirlwind, yea, when all his hail and his mighty storm shall beat upon you, it shall have no power over you to drag you down to the gulf of misery and endless wo, because of the rock upon which ye are built, which is a sure foundation, a foundation whereon if men build they cannot fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;mosiah-317&quot;&gt;Mosiah 3:17&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt; And moreover, I say unto you, that there shall be no other name given nor any other way nor means whereby salvation can come unto the children of men, only in and through the name of Christ, the Lord Omnipotent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;mosiah-49&quot;&gt;Mosiah 4:9&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt; Believe in God; believe that he is, and that he created all things, both in heaven and in earth; believe that he has all wisdom, and all power, both in heaven and in earth; believe that man doth not comprehend all the things which the Lord can comprehend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;mosiah-141-12-isaiah-53&quot;&gt;Mosiah 14:1-12 (Isaiah 53)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; Yea, even doth not Isaiah say: Who hath believed our report, and to whom is the arm of the Lord revealed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; For he shall grow up before him as a tender plant, and as a root out of dry ground; he hath no form nor comeliness; and when we shall see him there is no beauty that we should desire him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; He is despised and rejected of men; a man of sorrows, and acquainted with grief; and we hid as it were our faces from him; he was despised, and we esteemed him not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; Surely he has borne our griefs, and carried our sorrows; yet we did esteem him stricken, smitten of God, and afflicted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; But he was wounded for our transgressions, he was bruised for our iniquities; the chastisement of our peace was upon him; and with his stripes we are healed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; All we, like sheep, have gone astray; we have turned every one to his own way; and the Lord hath laid on him the iniquities of us all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; He was oppressed, and he was afflicted, yet he opened not his mouth; he is brought as a lamb to the slaughter, and as a sheep before her shearers is dumb so he opened not his mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; He was taken from prison and from judgment; and who shall declare his generation? For he was cut off out of the land of the living; for the transgressions of my people was he stricken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt; And he made his grave with the wicked, and with the rich in his death; because he had done no evil, neither was any deceit in his mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; Yet it pleased the Lord to bruise him; he hath put him to grief; when thou shalt make his soul an offering for sin he shall see his seed, he shall prolong his days, and the pleasure of the Lord shall prosper in his hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11&lt;/strong&gt; He shall see the travail of his soul, and shall be satisfied; by his knowledge shall my righteous servant justify many; for he shall bear their iniquities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt; Therefore will I divide him a portion with the great, and he shall divide the spoil with the strong; because he hath poured out his soul unto death; and he was numbered with the transgressors; and he bore the sins of many, and made intercession for the transgressors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;alma-710-16&quot;&gt;Alma 7:10-16&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; And behold, he shall be born of Mary, at Jerusalem which is the land of our forefathers, she being a virgin, a precious and chosen vessel, who shall be overshadowed and conceive by the power of the Holy Ghost, and bring forth a son, yea, even the Son of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11&lt;/strong&gt; And he shall go forth, suffering pains and afflictions and temptations of every kind; and this that the word might be fulfilled which saith he will take upon him the pains and the sicknesses of his people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt; And he will take upon him death, that he may loose the bands of death which bind his people; and he will take upon him their infirmities, that his bowels may be filled with mercy, according to the flesh, that he may know according to the flesh how to succor his people according to their infirmities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13&lt;/strong&gt; Now the Spirit knoweth all things; nevertheless the Son of God suffereth according to the flesh that he might take upon him the sins of his people, that he might blot out their transgressions according to the power of his deliverance; and now behold, this is the testimony which is in me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14&lt;/strong&gt; Now I say unto you that ye must repent, and be born again; for the Spirit saith if ye are not born again ye cannot inherit the kingdom of heaven; therefore come and be baptized unto repentance, that ye may be washed from your sins, that ye may have faith on the Lamb of God, who taketh away the sins of the world, who is mighty to save and to cleanse from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15&lt;/strong&gt; Yea, I say unto you come and fear not, and lay aside every sin, which easily doth beset you, which doth bind you down to destruction, yea, come and go forth, and show unto your God that ye are willing to repent of your sins and enter into a covenant with him to keep his commandments, and witness it unto him this day by going into the waters of baptism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16&lt;/strong&gt; And whosoever doeth this, and keepeth the commandments of God from thenceforth, the same will remember that I say unto him, yea, he will remember that I have said unto him, he shall have eternal life, according to the testimony of the Holy Spirit, which testifieth in me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;alma-1142-43&quot;&gt;Alma 11:42-43&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;42&lt;/strong&gt; Now, there is a death which is called a temporal death; and the death of Christ shall loose the bands of this temporal death, that all shall be raised from this temporal death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;43&lt;/strong&gt; The spirit and the body shall be reunited again in its perfect form; both limb and joint shall be restored to its proper frame, even as we now are at this time; and we shall be brought to stand before God, knowing even as we know now, and have a bright recollection of all our guilt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;alma-348-9&quot;&gt;Alma 34:8-9&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; And now, behold, I will testify unto you of myself that these things are true. Behold, I say unto you, that I do know that Christ shall come among the children of men, to take upon him the transgressions of his people, and that he shall atone for the sins of the world; for the Lord God hath spoken it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt; For it is expedient that an atonement should be made; for according to the great plan of the Eternal God there must be an atonement made, or else all mankind must unavoidably perish; yea, all are hardened; yea, all are fallen and are lost, and must perish except it be through the atonement which it is expedient should be made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;alma-3417&quot;&gt;Alma 34:17&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt; Therefore may God grant unto you, my brethren, that ye may begin to exercise your faith unto repentance, that ye begin to call upon his holy name, that he would have mercy upon you;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;alma-3432&quot;&gt;Alma 34:32&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;32&lt;/strong&gt; For behold, this life is the time for men to prepare to meet God; yea, behold the day of this life is the day for men to perform their labors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;alma-4023&quot;&gt;Alma 40:23&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23&lt;/strong&gt; The soul shall be restored to the body, and the body to the soul; yea, and every limb and joint shall be restored to its body; yea, even a hair of the head shall not be lost; but all things shall be restored to their proper and perfect frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;alma-4222-24&quot;&gt;Alma 42:22-24&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22&lt;/strong&gt; But there is a law given, and a punishment affixed, and a repentance granted; which repentance, mercy claimeth; otherwise, justice claimeth the creature and executeth the law, and the law inflicteth the punishment; if not so, the works of justice would be destroyed, and God would cease to be God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23&lt;/strong&gt; But God ceaseth not to be God, and mercy claimeth the penitent, and mercy cometh because of the atonement; and the atonement bringeth to pass the resurrection of the dead; and the resurrection of the dead bringeth back men into the presence of God; and thus they are restored into his presence, to be judged according to their works, according to the law and justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24&lt;/strong&gt; For behold, justice exerciseth all his demands, and also mercy claimeth all which is her own; and thus, none but the truly penitent are saved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;helaman-512&quot;&gt;Helaman 5:12&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt; And now, my sons, remember, remember that it is upon the rock of our Redeemer, who is Christ, the Son of God, that ye must build your foundation; that when the devil shall send forth his mighty winds, yea, his shafts in the whirlwind, yea, when all his hail and his mighty storm shall beat upon you, it shall have no power over you to drag you down to the gulf of misery and endless wo, because of the rock upon which ye are built, which is a sure foundation, a foundation whereon if men build they cannot fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-nephi-1113-15&quot;&gt;3 Nephi 11:13-15&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13&lt;/strong&gt; And it came to pass that the Lord spake unto them saying:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14&lt;/strong&gt; Arise and come forth unto me, that ye may thrust your hands into my side, and also that ye may feel the prints of the nails in my hands and in my feet, that ye may know that I am the God of Israel, and the God of the whole earth, and have been slain for the sins of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15&lt;/strong&gt; And it came to pass that the multitude went forth, and thrust their hands into his side, and did feel the prints of the nails in his hands and in his feet; and this they did do, going forth one by one until they had all gone forth, and did see with their eyes and did feel with their hands, and did know of a surety and did bear record, that it was he, of whom it was written by the prophets, that should come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-nephi-1123-26&quot;&gt;3 Nephi 11:23-26&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23&lt;/strong&gt; Verily I say unto you, that whoso repenteth of his sins through your words, and desireth to be baptized in my name, on this wise shall ye baptize them—Behold, ye shall go down and stand in the water, and in my name shall ye baptize them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24&lt;/strong&gt; And now behold, these are the words which ye shall say, calling them by name, saying:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25&lt;/strong&gt; Having authority given me of Jesus Christ, I baptize you in the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;26&lt;/strong&gt; And then shall ye immerse them in the water, and come forth again out of the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-nephi-2713-16&quot;&gt;3 Nephi 27:13-16&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13&lt;/strong&gt; Behold I have given unto you my gospel, and this is the gospel which I have given unto you—that I came into the world to do the will of my Father, because my Father sent me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14&lt;/strong&gt; And my Father sent me that I might be lifted up upon the cross; and after that I had been lifted up upon the cross, that I might draw all men unto me, that as I have been lifted up by men even so should men be lifted up by the Father, to stand before me, to be judged of their works, whether they be good or whether they be evil—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15&lt;/strong&gt; And for this cause have I been lifted up; therefore, according to the power of the Father I will draw all men unto me, that they may be judged according to their works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16&lt;/strong&gt; And it shall come to pass, that whoso repenteth and is baptized in my name shall be filled; and if he endureth to the end, behold, him will I hold guiltless before my Father at that day when I shall stand to judge the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-nephi-2720&quot;&gt;3 Nephi 27:20&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20&lt;/strong&gt; Now this is the commandment: Repent, all ye ends of the earth, and come unto me and be baptized in my name, that ye may be sanctified by the reception of the Holy Ghost, that ye may stand spotless before me at the last day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-nephi-2727&quot;&gt;3 Nephi 27:27&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;27&lt;/strong&gt; And know ye that ye shall be judges of this people, according to the judgment which I shall give unto you, which shall be just. Therefore, what manner of men ought ye to be? Verily I say unto you, even as I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;ether-124&quot;&gt;Ether 12:4&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; Wherefore, whoso believeth in God might with surety hope for a better world, yea, even a place at the right hand of God, which hope cometh of faith, maketh an anchor to the souls of men, which would make them sure and steadfast, always abounding in good works, being led to glorify God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;ether-126&quot;&gt;Ether 12:6&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; And now, I, Moroni, would speak somewhat concerning these things; I would show unto the world that faith is things which are hoped for and not seen; wherefore, dispute not because ye see not, for ye receive no witness until after the trial of your faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;ether-1227&quot;&gt;Ether 12:27&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;27&lt;/strong&gt; And if men come unto me I will show unto them their weakness. I give unto men weakness that they may be humble; and my grace is sufficient for all men that humble themselves before me; for if they humble themselves before me, and have faith in me, then will I make weak things become strong unto them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;moroni-61-6&quot;&gt;Moroni 6:1-6&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; And now I speak concerning baptism. Behold, elders, priests, and teachers were baptized; and they were not baptized save they brought forth fruit meet that they were worthy of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; Neither did they receive any unto baptism save they came forth with a broken heart and a contrite spirit, and witnessed unto the church that they truly repented of all their sins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; And none were received unto baptism save they took upon them the name of Christ, having a determination to serve him to the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; And after they had been received unto baptism, and were wrought upon and cleansed by the power of the Holy Ghost, they were numbered among the people of the church of Christ; and their names were taken, that they might be remembered and nourished by the good word of God, to keep them in the right way, to keep them continually watchful unto prayer, relying alone upon the merits of Christ, who was the author and the finisher of their faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; And the church did meet together oft, to fast and to pray, and to speak one with another concerning the welfare of their souls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; And they did meet together oft to partake of bread and wine, in remembrance of the Lord Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;moroni-745-48&quot;&gt;Moroni 7:45-48&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;45&lt;/strong&gt; And charity suffereth long, and is kind, and envieth not, and is not puffed up, seeketh not her own, is not easily provoked, thinketh no evil, and rejoiceth not in iniquity but rejoiceth in the truth, beareth all things, believeth all things, hopeth all things, endureth all things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;46&lt;/strong&gt; Wherefore, my beloved brethren, if ye have not charity, ye are nothing, for charity never faileth. Wherefore, cleave unto charity, which is the greatest of all, for all things must fail—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;47&lt;/strong&gt; But charity is the pure love of Christ, and it endureth forever; and whoso is found possessed of it at the last day, it shall be well with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;48&lt;/strong&gt; Wherefore, my beloved brethren, pray unto the Father with all the energy of heart, that ye may be filled with this love, which he hath bestowed upon all who are true followers of his Son, Jesus Christ; that ye may become the sons of God; that when he shall appear we shall be like him, for we shall see him as he is; that we may have this hope; that we may be purified even as he is pure. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;moroni-810-12&quot;&gt;Moroni 8:10-12&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; Behold I say unto you that this thing shall ye teach—repentance and baptism unto those who are accountable and capable of committing sin; yea, teach parents that they must repent and be baptized, and humble themselves as their little children, and they shall all be saved with their little children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11&lt;/strong&gt; And their little children need no repentance, neither baptism. Behold, baptism is unto repentance to the fulfilling the commandments unto the remission of sins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt; But little children are alive in Christ, even from the foundation of the world; if not so, God is a partial God, and also a changeable God, and a respecter to persons; for how many little children have died without baptism!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;moroni-103-5&quot;&gt;Moroni 10:3-5&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; Behold, I would exhort you that when ye shall read these things, if it be wisdom in God that ye should read them, that ye would remember how merciful the Lord hath been unto the children of men, from the creation of Adam even down until the time that ye shall receive these things, and ponder it in your hearts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; And when ye shall receive these things, I would exhort you that ye would ask God, the Eternal Father, in the name of Christ, if these things are not true; and if ye shall ask with a sincere heart, with real intent, having faith in Christ, he will manifest the truth of it unto you, by the power of the Holy Ghost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; And by the power of the Holy Ghost ye may know the truth of all things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;moroni-1032-33&quot;&gt;Moroni 10:32-33&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;32&lt;/strong&gt; Yea, come unto Christ, and be perfected in him, and deny yourselves of all ungodliness; and if ye shall deny yourselves of all ungodliness, and love God with all your might, mind and strength, then is his grace sufficient for you, that by his grace ye may be perfect in Christ; and if by the grace of God ye are perfect in Christ, ye can in nowise deny the power of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;33&lt;/strong&gt; And again, if ye by the grace of God are perfect in Christ, and deny not his power, then are ye sanctified in Christ by the grace of God, through the shedding of the blood of Christ, which is in the covenant of the Father unto the remission of your sins, that ye become holy, without spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot; id=&quot;doctrine--covenants&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Doctrine &amp;amp; Covenants&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;dc-130-32&quot;&gt;D&amp;amp;C 1:30-32&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;30&lt;/strong&gt; And also those to whom these commandments were given, might have power to lay the foundation of this church, and to bring it forth out of obscurity and out of darkness, the only true and living church upon the face of the whole earth, with which I, the Lord, am well pleased, speaking unto the church collectively and not individually—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;31&lt;/strong&gt; For I the Lord cannot look upon sin with the least degree of allowance;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;32&lt;/strong&gt; Nevertheless, he that repents and does the commandments of the Lord shall be forgiven;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dc-21-3&quot;&gt;D&amp;amp;C 2:1-3&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; Behold, I will reveal unto you the Priesthood, by the hand of Elijah the prophet, before the coming of the great and dreadful day of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; And he shall plant in the hearts of the children the promises made to the fathers, and the hearts of the children shall turn to their fathers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; If it were not so, the whole earth would be utterly wasted at his coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dc-41-7&quot;&gt;D&amp;amp;C 4:1-7&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; Now behold, a marvelous work is about to come forth among the children of men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; Therefore, O ye that embark in the service of God, see that ye serve him with all your heart, might, mind and strength, that ye may stand blameless before God at the last day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; Therefore, if ye have desires to serve God ye are called to the work;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; For behold the field is white already to harvest; and lo, he that thrusteth in his sickle with his might, the same layeth up in store that he perisheth not, but bringeth salvation to his soul;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; And faith, hope, charity and love, with an eye single to the glory of God, qualify him for the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; Remember faith, virtue, knowledge, temperance, patience, brotherly kindness, godliness, charity, humility, diligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; Ask, and ye shall receive; knock, and it shall be opened unto you. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dc-82-3&quot;&gt;D&amp;amp;C 8:2-3&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; Yea, behold, I will tell you in your mind and in your heart, by the Holy Ghost, which shall come upon you and which shall dwell in your heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; Now, behold, this is the spirit of revelation; behold, this is the spirit by which Moses brought the children of Israel through the Red Sea on dry ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dc-131&quot;&gt;D&amp;amp;C 13:1&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; Upon you my fellow servants, in the name of Messiah I confer the Priesthood of Aaron, which holds the keys of the ministering of angels, and of the gospel of repentance, and of baptism by immersion for the remission of sins; and this shall never be taken again from the earth, until the sons of Levi do offer again an offering unto the Lord in righteousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dc-147&quot;&gt;D&amp;amp;C 14:7&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; And, if you keep my commandments and endure to the end you shall have eternal life, which gift is the greatest of all the gifts of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dc-1911-1215-20&quot;&gt;D&amp;amp;C 19:11-12,15-20&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11&lt;/strong&gt; Eternal punishment is God’s punishment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt; Endless punishment is God’s punishment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15&lt;/strong&gt; Therefore I command you to repent—repent, lest I smite you by the rod of my mouth, and by my wrath, and by my anger, and your sufferings be sore—how sore you know not, how exquisite you know not, yea, how hard to bear you know not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16&lt;/strong&gt; For behold, I, God, have suffered these things for all, that they might not suffer if they would repent;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt; But if they would not repent they must suffer even as I;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18&lt;/strong&gt; Which suffering caused myself, even God, the greatest of all, to tremble because of pain, and to bleed at every pore, and to suffer both body and spirit—and would that I might not drink the bitter cup, and shrink—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19&lt;/strong&gt; Nevertheless, glory be to the Father, and I partook and finished my preparations unto the children of men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20&lt;/strong&gt; Wherefore, I command you again to repent, lest I humble you with my almighty power; and that you confess your sins, lest you suffer these punishments of which I have spoken, of which in the smallest, yea, even in the least degree you have tasted at the time I withdrew my Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dc-2037&quot;&gt;D&amp;amp;C 20:37&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;37&lt;/strong&gt; *And again, by way of commandment to the church concerning the manner of baptism—All those who humble themselves before God, and desire to be baptized, and come forth with broken hearts and contrite spirits, and witness before the church that they have truly repented of all their sins, and are willing to take upon them the name of Jesus Christ, having a determination to serve him to the end, and truly manifest by their works that they have received of the Spirit of Christ unto the remission of their sins, shall be received by baptism into his church.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dc-2077&quot;&gt;D&amp;amp;C 20:77&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;77&lt;/strong&gt; O God, the Eternal Father, we ask thee in the name of thy Son, Jesus Christ, to bless and sanctify this bread to the souls of all those who partake of it, that they may eat in remembrance of the body of thy Son, and witness unto thee, O God, the Eternal Father, that they are willing to take upon them the name of thy Son, and always remember him and keep his commandments which he has given them; that they may always have his Spirit to be with them. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dc-2079&quot;&gt;D&amp;amp;C 20:79&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;79&lt;/strong&gt; O God, the Eternal Father, we ask thee in the name of thy Son, Jesus Christ, to bless and sanctify this wine to the souls of all those who drink of it, that they may do it in remembrance of the blood of thy Son, which was shed for them; that they may witness unto thee, O God, the Eternal Father, that they do always remember him, that they may have his Spirit to be with them. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dc-426&quot;&gt;D&amp;amp;C 42:6&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; And ye shall go forth in the power of my Spirit, preaching my gospel, two by two, in my name, lifting up your voices as with the sound of a trump, declaring my word like unto angels of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dc-453-5&quot;&gt;D&amp;amp;C 45:3-5&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; Listen to him who is the advocate with the Father, who is pleading your cause before him—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; Saying: Father, behold the sufferings and death of him who did no sin, in whom thou wast well pleased; behold the blood of thy Son which was shed, the blood of him whom thou gavest that thyself might be glorified;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; Wherefore, Father, spare these my brethren that believe on my name, that they may come unto me and have everlasting life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dc-765-10&quot;&gt;D&amp;amp;C 76:5-10&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; For thus saith the Lord—I, the Lord, am merciful and gracious unto those who fear me, and delight to honor those who serve me in righteousness and in truth unto the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; Great shall be their reward and eternal shall be their glory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; And to them will I reveal all mysteries, yea, all the hidden mysteries of my kingdom from days of old, and for ages to come, will I make known unto them the good pleasure of my will concerning all things pertaining to my kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; Yea, even the wonders of eternity shall they know, and things to come will I show them, even the things of many generations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt; And their wisdom shall be great, and their understanding reach to heaven; and before them the wisdom of the wise shall perish, and the understanding of the prudent shall come to naught.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; For by my Spirit will I enlighten them, and by my power will I make known unto them the secrets of my will—yea, even those things which eye has not seen, nor ear heard, nor yet entered into the heart of man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dc-7622-24&quot;&gt;D&amp;amp;C 76:22-24&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22&lt;/strong&gt; And now, after the many testimonies which have been given of him, this is the testimony, last of all, which we give of him: That he lives!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23&lt;/strong&gt; For we saw him, even on the right hand of God; and we heard the voice bearing record that he is the Only Begotten of the Father—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24&lt;/strong&gt; That by him, and through him, and of him, the worlds are and were created, and the inhabitants thereof are begotten sons and daughters unto God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dc-8433-44&quot;&gt;D&amp;amp;C 84:33-44&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;33&lt;/strong&gt; For whoso is faithful unto the obtaining these two priesthoods of which I have spoken, and the magnifying their calling, are sanctified by the Spirit unto the renewing of their bodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;34&lt;/strong&gt; They become the sons of Moses and of Aaron and the seed of Abraham, and the church and kingdom, and the elect of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;35&lt;/strong&gt; And also all they who receive this priesthood receive me, saith the Lord;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;36&lt;/strong&gt; For he that receiveth my servants receiveth me;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;37&lt;/strong&gt; And he that receiveth me receiveth my Father;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;38&lt;/strong&gt; And he that receiveth my Father receiveth my Father’s kingdom; therefore all that my Father hath shall be given unto him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;39&lt;/strong&gt; And this is according to the oath and covenant which belongeth to the priesthood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;40&lt;/strong&gt; Therefore, all those who receive the priesthood, receive this oath and covenant of my Father, which he cannot break, neither can it be moved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;41&lt;/strong&gt; But whoso breaketh this covenant after he hath received it, and altogether turneth therefrom, shall not have forgiveness of sins in this world nor in the world to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;42&lt;/strong&gt; And wo unto all those who come not unto this priesthood which ye have received, which I now confirm upon you who are present this day, by mine own voice out of the heavens; and even I have given the heavenly hosts and mine angels charge concerning you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;43&lt;/strong&gt; And I now give unto you a commandment to beware concerning yourselves, to give diligent heed to the words of eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;44&lt;/strong&gt; For you shall live by every word that proceedeth forth from the mouth of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dc-8918-21&quot;&gt;D&amp;amp;C 89:18-21&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18&lt;/strong&gt; And all saints who remember to keep and do these sayings, walking in obedience to the commandments, shall receive health in their navel and marrow to their bones;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19&lt;/strong&gt; And shall find wisdom and great treasures of knowledge, even hidden treasures;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20&lt;/strong&gt; And shall run and not be weary, and shall walk and not faint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21&lt;/strong&gt; And I, the Lord, give unto them a promise, that the destroying angel shall pass by them, as the children of Israel, and not slay them. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dc-1211-15&quot;&gt;D&amp;amp;C 121:1-15&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; O God, where art thou? And where is the pavilion that covereth thy hiding place?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; How long shall thy hand be stayed, and thine eye, yea thy pure eye, behold from the eternal heavens the wrongs of thy people and of thy servants, and thine ear be penetrated with their cries?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; Yea, O Lord, how long shall they suffer these wrongs and unlawful oppressions, before thine heart shall be softened toward them, and thy bowels be moved with compassion toward them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; O Lord God Almighty, maker of heaven, earth, and seas, and of all things that in them are, and who controllest and subjectest the devil, and the dark and benighted dominion of Sheol—stretch forth thy hand; let thine eye pierce; let thy pavilion be taken up; let thy hiding place no longer be covered; let thine ear be inclined; let thine heart be softened, and thy bowels moved with compassion toward us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; Let thine anger be kindled against our enemies; and, in the fury of thine heart, with thy sword avenge us of our wrongs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; Remember thy suffering saints, O our God; and thy servants will rejoice in thy name forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; My son, peace be unto thy soul; thine adversity and thine afflictions shall be but a small moment;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; And then, if thou endure it well, God shall exalt thee on high; thou shalt triumph over all thy foes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt; Thy friends do stand by thee, and they shall hail thee again with warm hearts and friendly hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; Thou art not yet as Job; thy friends do not contend against thee, neither charge thee with transgression, as they did Job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11&lt;/strong&gt; And they who do charge thee with transgression, their hope shall be blasted, and their prospects shall melt away as the hoar frost melteth before the burning rays of the rising sun;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt; And also that God hath set his hand and seal to change the times and seasons, and to blind their minds, that they may not understand his marvelous workings; that he may prove them also and take them in their own craftiness;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13&lt;/strong&gt; Also because their hearts are corrupted, and the things which they are willing to bring upon others, and love to have others suffer, may come upon themselves to the very uttermost;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14&lt;/strong&gt; That they may be disappointed also, and their hopes may be cut off;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15&lt;/strong&gt; And not many years hence, that they and their posterity shall be swept from under heaven, saith God, that not one of them is left to stand by the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dc-12134-46&quot;&gt;D&amp;amp;C 121:34-46&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;34&lt;/strong&gt; Behold, there are many called, but few are chosen. And why are they not chosen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;35&lt;/strong&gt; Because their hearts are set so much upon the things of this world, and aspire to the honors of men, that they do not learn this one lesson—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;36&lt;/strong&gt; That the rights of the priesthood are inseparably connected with the powers of heaven, and that the powers of heaven cannot be controlled nor handled only upon the principles of righteousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;37&lt;/strong&gt; That they may be conferred upon us, it is true; but when we undertake to cover our sins, or to gratify our pride, our vain ambition, or to exercise control or dominion or compulsion upon the souls of the children of men, in any degree of unrighteousness, behold, the heavens withdraw themselves; the Spirit of the Lord is grieved; and when it is withdrawn, Amen to the priesthood or the authority of that man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;38&lt;/strong&gt; Behold, ere he is aware, he is left unto himself, to kick against the pricks, to persecute the saints, and to fight against God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;39&lt;/strong&gt; We have learned by sad experience that it is the nature and disposition of almost all men, as soon as they get a little authority, as they suppose, they will immediately begin to exercise unrighteous dominion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;40&lt;/strong&gt; Hence many are called, but few are chosen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;41&lt;/strong&gt; No power or influence can or ought to be maintained by virtue of the priesthood, only by persuasion, by long-suffering, by gentleness and meekness, and by love unfeigned;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;42&lt;/strong&gt; By kindness, and pure knowledge, which shall greatly enlarge the soul without hypocrisy, and without guile—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;43&lt;/strong&gt; Reproving betimes with sharpness, when moved upon by the Holy Ghost; and then showing forth afterwards an increase of love toward him whom thou hast reproved, lest he esteem thee to be his enemy;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;44&lt;/strong&gt; That he may know that thy faithfulness is stronger than the cords of death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;45&lt;/strong&gt; Let thy bowels also be full of charity towards all men, and to the household of faith, and let virtue garnish thy thoughts unceasingly; then shall thy confidence wax strong in the presence of God; and the doctrine of the priesthood shall distil upon thy soul as the dews from heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;46&lt;/strong&gt; The Holy Ghost shall be thy constant companion, and thy scepter an unchanging scepter of righteousness and truth; and thy dominion shall be an everlasting dominion, and without compulsory means it shall flow unto thee forever and ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dc-1272&quot;&gt;D&amp;amp;C 127:2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; And as for the perils which I am called to pass through, they seem but a small thing to me, as the envy and wrath of man have been my common lot all the days of my life; and for what cause it seems mysterious, unless I was ordained from before the foundation of the world for some good end, or bad, as you may choose to call it. Judge ye for yourselves. God knoweth all these things, whether it be good or bad. But nevertheless, deep water is what I am wont to swim in. It all has become a second nature to me; and I feel, like Paul, to glory in tribulation; for to this day has the God of my fathers delivered me out of them all, and will deliver me from henceforth; for behold, and lo, I shall triumph over all my enemies, for the Lord God hath spoken it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dc-12822&quot;&gt;D&amp;amp;C 128:22&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22&lt;/strong&gt; Brethren, shall we not go on in so great a cause? Go forward and not backward. Courage, brethren; and on, on to the victory! Let your hearts rejoice, and be exceedingly glad. Let the earth break forth into singing. Let the dead speak forth anthems of eternal praise to the King Immanuel, who hath ordained, before the world was, that which would enable us to redeem them out of their prison; for the prisoners shall go free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dc-13018-23&quot;&gt;D&amp;amp;C 130:18-23&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18&lt;/strong&gt; Whatever principle of intelligence we attain unto in this life, it will rise with us in the resurrection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19&lt;/strong&gt; And if a person gains more knowledge and intelligence in this life through his diligence and obedience than another, he will have so much the advantage in the world to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20&lt;/strong&gt; There is a law, irrevocably decreed in heaven before the foundations of this world, upon which all blessings are predicated—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21&lt;/strong&gt; And when we obtain any blessing from God, it is by obedience to that law upon which it is predicated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22&lt;/strong&gt; The Father has a body of flesh and bones as tangible as man’s; the Son also; but the Holy Ghost has not a body of flesh and bones, but is a personage of Spirit. Were it not so, the Holy Ghost could not dwell in us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23&lt;/strong&gt; A man may receive the Holy Ghost, and it may descend upon him and not tarry with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dc-1353&quot;&gt;D&amp;amp;C 135:3&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; Joseph Smith, the Prophet and Seer of the Lord, has done more, save Jesus only, for the salvation of men in this world, than any other man that ever lived in it. In the short space of twenty years, he has brought forth the Book of Mormon, which he translated by the gift and power of God, and has been the means of publishing it on two continents; has sent the fulness of the everlasting gospel, which it contained, to the four quarters of the earth; has brought forth the revelations and commandments which compose this book of Doctrine and Covenants, and many other wise documents and instructions for the benefit of the children of men; gathered many thousands of the Latter-day Saints, founded a great city, and left a fame and name that cannot be slain. He lived great, and he died great in the eyes of God and his people; and like most of the Lord’s anointed in ancient times, has sealed his mission and his works with his own blood; and so has his brother Hyrum. In life they were not divided, and in death they were not separated!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot; id=&quot;pearl-of-great-price&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Pearl of Great Price&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;moses-139&quot;&gt;Moses 1:39&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;39&lt;/strong&gt; For behold, this is my work and my glory—to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;abraham-322-28&quot;&gt;Abraham 3:22-28&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22&lt;/strong&gt; Now the Lord had shown unto me, Abraham, the intelligences that were organized before the world was; and among all these there were many of the noble and great ones;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23&lt;/strong&gt; And God saw these souls that they were good, and he stood in the midst of them, and he said: These I will make my rulers; for he stood among those that were spirits, and he saw that they were good; and he said unto me: Abraham, thou art one of them; thou wast chosen before thou wast born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24&lt;/strong&gt; And there stood one among them that was like unto God, and he said unto those who were with him: We will go down, for there is space there, and we will take of these materials, and we will make an earth whereon these may dwell;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25&lt;/strong&gt; And we will prove them herewith, to see if they will do all things whatsoever the Lord their God shall command them;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;26&lt;/strong&gt; And they who keep their first estate shall be added upon; and they who keep not their first estate shall not have glory in the same kingdom with those who keep their first estate; and they who keep their second estate shall have glory added upon their heads for ever and ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;27&lt;/strong&gt; And the Lord said: Whom shall I send? And one answered like unto the Son of Man: Here am I, send me. And another answered and said: Here am I, send me. And the Lord said: I will send the first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;28&lt;/strong&gt; And the second was angry, and kept not his first estate; and, at that day, many followed after him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;joseph-smithhistory-1813-20&quot;&gt;Joseph Smith—History 1:8,13-20&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; During this time of great excitement my mind was called up to serious reflection and great uneasiness; but though my feelings were deep and often poignant, still I kept myself aloof from all these parties, though I attended their several meetings as often as occasion would permit. In process of time my mind became somewhat partial to the Methodist sect, and I felt some desire to be united with them; but so great were the confusion and strife among the different denominations, that it was impossible for a person young as I was, and so unacquainted with men and things, to come to any certain conclusion who was right and who was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11&lt;/strong&gt; While I was laboring under the extreme difficulties caused by the contests of these parties of religionists, I was one day reading the Epistle of James, [first chapter and fifth verse], which reads: If any of you lack wisdom, let him ask of God, that giveth to all men liberally, and upbraideth not; and it shall be given him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt; Never did any passage of scripture come with more power to the heart of man than this did at this time to mine. It seemed to enter with great force into every feeling of my heart. I reflected on it again and again, knowing that if any person needed wisdom from God, I did; for how to act I did not know, and unless I could get more wisdom than I then had, I would never know; for the teachers of religion of the different sects understood the same passages of scripture so differently as to destroy all confidence in settling the question by an appeal to the Bible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13&lt;/strong&gt; At length I came to the conclusion that I must either remain in darkness and confusion, or else I must do as James directs, that is, ask of God. I at length came to the determination to “ask of God,” concluding that if he gave wisdom to them that lacked wisdom, and would give liberally, and not upbraid, I might venture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14&lt;/strong&gt; So, in accordance with this, my determination to ask of God, I retired to the woods to make the attempt. It was on the morning of a beautiful, clear day, early in the spring of eighteen hundred and twenty. It was the first time in my life that I had made such an attempt, for amidst all my anxieties I had never as yet made the attempt to pray vocally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15&lt;/strong&gt; After I had retired to the place where I had previously designed to go, having looked around me, and finding myself alone, I kneeled down and began to offer up the desires of my heart to God. I had scarcely done so, when immediately I was seized upon by some power which entirely overcame me, and had such an astonishing influence over me as to bind my tongue so that I could not speak. Thick darkness gathered around me, and it seemed to me for a time as if I were doomed to sudden destruction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16&lt;/strong&gt; But, exerting all my powers to call upon God to deliver me out of the power of this enemy which had seized upon me, and at the very moment when I was ready to sink into despair and abandon myself to destruction—not to an imaginary ruin, but to the power of some actual being from the unseen world, who had such marvelous power as I had never before felt in any being—just at this moment of great alarm, I saw a pillar of light exactly over my head, above the brightness of the sun, which descended gradually until it fell upon me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt; It no sooner appeared than I found myself delivered from the enemy which held me bound. When the light rested upon me I saw two Personages, whose brightness and glory defy all description, standing above me in the air. One of them spake unto me, calling me by name and said, pointing to the other—&lt;em&gt;This is My&lt;/em&gt; Beloved &lt;em&gt;*Son&lt;/em&gt;. Hear Him!*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18&lt;/strong&gt; My object in going to inquire of the Lord was to know which of all the sects was right, that I might know which to join. No sooner, therefore, did I get possession of myself, so as to be able to speak, than I asked the Personages who stood above me in the light, which of all the sects was right (for at this time it had never entered into my heart that all were wrong)—and which I should join.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19&lt;/strong&gt; I was answered that I must join none of them, for they were all wrong; and the Personage who addressed me said that all their creeds were an abomination in his sight; that those professors were all corrupt; that: “they draw near to me with their lips, but their hearts are far from me, they teach for doctrines the commandments of men, having a form of godliness, but they deny the power thereof.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20&lt;/strong&gt; He again forbade me to join with any of them; and many other things did he say unto me, which I cannot write at this time. When I came to myself again, I found myself lying on my back, looking up into heaven. When the light had departed, I had no strength; but soon recovering in some degree, I went home. And as I leaned up to the fireplace, mother inquired what the matter was. I replied, “Never mind, all is well—I am well enough off.” I then said to my mother, “I have learned for myself that Presbyterianism is not true.” It seems as though the adversary was aware, at a very early period of my life, that I was destined to prove a disturber and an annoyer of his kingdom; else why should the powers of darkness combine against me? Why the opposition and persecution that arose against me, almost in my infancy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-articles-of-faith&quot;&gt;The Articles of Faith&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; We believe in God, the Eternal Father, and in His Son, Jesus Christ, and in the Holy Ghost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; We believe that men will be punished for their own sins, and not for Adam’s transgression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; We believe that through the Atonement of Christ, all mankind may be saved, by obedience to the laws and ordinances of the Gospel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; We believe that the first principles and ordinances of the Gospel are: first, Faith in the Lord Jesus Christ; second, Repentance; third, Baptism by immersion for the remission of sins; fourth, Laying on of hands for the gift of the Holy Ghost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; We believe that a man must be called of God, by prophecy, and by the laying on of hands by those who are in authority, to preach the Gospel and administer in the ordinances thereof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; We believe in the same organization that existed in the Primitive Church, namely, apostles, prophets, pastors, teachers, evangelists, and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; We believe in the gift of tongues, prophecy, revelation, visions, healing, interpretation of tongues, and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; We believe the Bible to be the word of God as far as it is translated correctly; we also believe the Book of Mormon to be the word of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt; We believe all that God has revealed, all that He does now reveal, and we believe that He will yet reveal many great and important things pertaining to the Kingdom of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; We believe in the literal gathering of Israel and in the restoration of the Ten Tribes; that Zion (the New Jerusalem) will be built upon the American continent; that Christ will reign personally upon the earth; and, that the earth will be renewed and receive its paradisiacal glory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11&lt;/strong&gt; We claim the privilege of worshiping Almighty God according to the dictates of our own conscience, and allow all men the same privilege, let them worship how, where, or what they may.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt; We believe in being subject to kings, presidents, rulers, and magistrates, in obeying, honoring, and sustaining the law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13&lt;/strong&gt; We believe in being honest, true, chaste, benevolent, virtuous, and in doing good to all men; indeed, we may say that we follow the admonition of Paul—We believe all things, we hope all things, we have endured many things, and hope to be able to endure all things. If there is anything virtuous, lovely, or of good report or praiseworthy, we seek after these things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot; id=&quot;miscellaneous&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-family-a-proclamation-to-the-world--paragraph-7&quot;&gt;The Family: A Proclamation to the World — Paragraph 7&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The family is ordained of God. Marriage between man and woman is essential to His eternal plan. Children are entitled to birth within the bonds of matrimony, and to be reared by a father and a mother who honor marital vows with complete fidelity. Happiness in family life is most likely to be achieved when founded upon the teachings of the Lord Jesus Christ. Successful marriages and families are established and maintained on principles of faith, prayer, repentance, forgiveness, respect, love, compassion, work, and wholesome recreational activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-standard-of-truth-by-joseph-smith-jr&quot;&gt;The Standard of Truth by Joseph Smith Jr.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Standard of Truth has been erected; no unhallowed hand can stop the work from progressing; persecutions may rage, mobs may combine, armies may assemble, calumny may defame, but the truth of God will go forth boldly, nobly, and independent, till it has penetrated every continent, visited every clime, swept every country, and sounded in every ear, till the purposes of God shall be accomplished, and the Great Jehovah shall say the work is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;teachings-of-presidents-of-the-church-joseph-smith-2007-330&quot;&gt;Teachings of Presidents of the Church: Joseph Smith [2007], 330&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all that has been said, the greatest and most important duty is to preach the Gospel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-teachings-of-harold-b-lee-280&quot;&gt;The Teachings of Harold B. Lee, 280.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important of the Lord’s work you will ever do will be within the walls of your own homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;mormon-doctrine-2d-ed-1966-p-664---bruce-r-mcconkie&quot;&gt;Mormon Doctrine, 2d ed., 1966, p. 664. - Bruce R. McConkie&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sacrifice pertains to mortality; in the eternal sense there is none. Sacrifice involves giving up the things of this world because of the promises of blessings to be gained in a better world. In the eternal perspective there is no sacrifice in giving up all things—even including the laying down of one’s life—if eternal life is gained through such a course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-gift-of-the-holy-ghost---a-sure-compass-ensign-april-1996-4&quot;&gt;The Gift of the Holy Ghost - A Sure Compass, Ensign, April 1996, 4&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Holy Ghost bears witness to us of the truth and impresses upon our souls the reality of God the Father and His Son, Jesus Christ, so surely that no earthly power or authority can separate us from that knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;roseville-california-mission-statement&quot;&gt;Roseville California Mission Statement&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our mission is to bring souls to Christ and to a knowledge of His Atonement. We will pray fervently, work diligently, abide in obedience, love everyone, and become one in the Savior… ‘become the sons of God, even one in me as I am one in the Father, as the Father is one in me, that we may be one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;my-missionary-commission-by-bruce-r-mcconkie&quot;&gt;My Missionary Commission by Bruce R. McConkie&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am called of God. My authority is above that of the kings of the earth. By revelation I have been selected as a personal representative of the Lord Jesus Christ.
He is my master and He has chosen me to represent Him. To stand in His place. To say and do what He Himself would say and do if He personally were ministering to the very people to whom He has sent me.
My voice is His voice and my acts are His acts. My words are His words and my doctrine is His doctrine.
My commission is to do what He wants done, to say what He wants said, to be a living modern witness in word and deed of the divinity of His great and marvelous latter-day work. How great is my calling!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;W&lt;/span&gt;hen I was a missionary in the California, Roseville mission for The Church
of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints I spent many hours memorizing scripture. My mission president Danel Bachman was a 
Mormon scholar and influenced the time I spent studying the history, doctrine and scripture of the Mormon church. I had
hundreds of 3x5 cards to assist me in memorizing scripture but I lost them over the years. Here are the majority of scripture
I had or still have memorized:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://NotYourMothersMormonism.com/blog/memorized-scripture/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://NotYourMothersMormonism.com/blog/memorized-scripture/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
